翻译:花泽かな、GIN、AI、偶像鲨、裏spartan、ZWX、扣酱
校对:花泽かな、ばはやし、AI、扣酱　时轴:断弦、蓓蓓 、小病　片源:AI　压制:VCB-Studio
本字幕由幻之字幕组与诸神字幕组制作仅供试看使用不得将本片用于商业用途请与下载24小时之内删除
如果您喜欢本作品请支持购买正版一切利用本片进行商业违法的行为与字幕组无关
The stalk is standing in the tea.
茶柱が立ったわ
Do you know what they say in England?
イギリスのこんな言い伝えを知ってる？
When the stalk stands in the tea, you will have terrific visitors.
「茶柱が立つと　ステキな訪問者が現れる」
Excuse me, but the visitors have already arrived.
お言葉ですが　もう現れています
I'm not sure if I'd call them terrific.
ステキかどうかはさておき
いいぞ　やれー
そのまま突撃しろー
Ooarai Girls' Academy Celebratory Exhibition Match
大洗女子学园夺冠纪念表演赛
油断するなー
Exhibition matches are so cool!
エキシビションって　なんかかっこいいね
Cool...
かっこいい…
Is it really important that Panzerfahren is cool?
それは戦車道にとって　大切なことかな
So why are you doing Panzerfahren, Mika?
じゃあミカは何で戦車道やってんの？
It features every important part of life.
戦車道は人生の大切な　すべてのことが詰まってるんだよ
Most are simply not aware of it.
でも　ほとんどの人が　それに気づかないんだ
What are you talking about?
何よ　それ
This may be a friendly, but I believe you are taking it too lightly.
いくら親善試合とはいえ　油断しすぎたのでは
This encirclement will not be as easy to break as a scone.
この包囲網はスコーンを割るように　簡単には砕けません
Calm yourselves.
落ち着きなさい
I sadly must repeat myself,
いかなる時も優雅…
but this is St. Gloriana's way of Panzerfahren.
それが聖グロリアーナの戦車道よ
They're not firing at us.
応戦してこないね
It's like they're not under any pressure.
相手は何だか余裕だよ
I'm sure they're drinking black tea.
きっと紅茶飲んでるんですよ
Should I make green tea?
わたくしたちは緑茶でも淹れます？
I want a milk shake!
ミルクセーキがいい
We can make it with the eggs
and the milk in the cooler box.
卵も牛乳もクーラーボックスに　入れてきましたから
作れますよ
Excellent.
すごいです
で　どうする？　みぽりん
What do you want to do, Miho?
Stop firing.
発砲をやめてください
It will take some time until
the other detachments arrive here.
別動隊がこちらに到達するには　まだ時間がかかります
Advance slowly to surround them more closely.
今のうちにゆっくり前進して　包囲の輪を狭くしていきます
We will use the geography to move in
and finish them from a closer distance.
安全な地形を確保しつつ
近距離での確実な撃破を目指しましょう
Roger.
かしこまりました
We have time, so don't rush it.
時間はあるので慎重に
Panzer vor!
パンツァーフォー
Um...
あの…
Commander Nishizumi,
what does Panzer vor mean?
西住隊長
「ぱんつぁーふぉー」って何ですか？
Oh, Panzer vor means Panzer vor.
ああ　戦車前進ってことです
I see!
なるほど
そういう意味ですか
I learned something.
勉強になりました
Does Chihatan Academy really know what they're doing?
大丈夫か　知波単学園は…
They're a bit weird, aren't they?
ちょっと変わってるよね～
They're all so serious and brave, though...
でもみんな真面目そうだし　勇敢だから
All tanks, advance!
戦車前進
Tank, advance!
戦車前進　戦車前進　戦車前進
戦車前進
Once more, then.
ではもう一度
Panzer vor!
パンツァーフォー
All tanks, stop.
全車停止
Duck team, ready to fire.
アヒルチーム　砲撃準備　完了
Rabbit team, we're ready.
ウサギチーム　準備ＯＫです
We're ready.
大丈夫だにゃー
Ready to fire.
砲撃準備よし
Bring it on.
始めちゃっていーよー
The assault group composed of Ooarai and Chihatan is in position.
大洗・知波単連合　攻撃部隊の準備整いました
How is the defense group doing?
守備隊の状況　どうなってますか？
Having fun here.
じわじわ来てるよー
Um...
え～と
Maybe another five minutes.
あと５分ってとこかな
She said we can give you maybe another
five minutes. So, not much longer, anyway.
あと５分だって
でも　どっちにしても　そんなにはもたないからね
Roger.
了解
Fire!
砲撃開始
Chihatan Academy has knocked out two Mathilda IIs!
知波単学園２号車　マチルダⅡ　命中
St. Gloriana has been smashed!
聖グロリアーナ撃破
A brilliant victory for our army!
快挙であります　大戦果であります
Wow! The last time we got
white flags was on the Stuarts!
すごいな
聖グロから白旗なんて　スチュアート以来だ
Miss Nishi! We must mount a frontal assault now!
西殿　あとは突撃あるのみです
I agree! Frontal assaults are our tradition!
そのとおり　突撃は我が校の伝統です
What else is there but a frontal assault?
突撃以外　何がありましょうぞ
Um, is that really such a good...
いや　どうかな？
Attack!
突撃
Attack them and die with honor!
突撃して潔く散りましょうぞ
No, don't die!
ややや　散ったらダメだろう
Show them our Chihatan spirit!
知波単魂を世に知らしめよう
Victory is with us!
勝利は我にあり
Well, all right.
ま　いいか
Attack!
よし　とっかん
Um, Nishi?
あの　西さん
The scone has decided to break itself.
勝手にスコーンが割れたわね
Now we must only eat the pieces.
あとは　おいしく頂くだけですか
And the sandwiches will be ready soon.
それに　もうすぐサンドイッチも出来上がるわ
Fire.
砲撃
くそ
Shit!
We almost had them.
あとひと息なのに
Should we really keep this up?
果たして我々は　このままでいいのだろうか
We shouldn't...
いや　よくない
No, we should!
いや　いい
Oh, my...
Oh, no!
まずい　このままじゃ
Chihatan's first detachment
has decisively rushed the enemy!
我が知波単第一中隊が　突撃を敢行したらしいぞ
All right! Don't fall behind!
よし　我々も後れを取るな
As if!
取らいでか
Attack!
突撃
Hey, wait!
ちょっと待った
Nagura!
先輩殿
We will follow them!
我々もあとに続くであります
Forward!
戦車前進
No, stay here. You're all so reckless.
だからダメだって　みんな無謀すぎ
行かせてください
Let us go! How could we look into their eyes later?
このままでは　みんなに合わす顔がありません
Aggressive attacks are fine,
but what's the point if you get taken out?
アグレッシブに　攻めるのもいいけど
リタイアしちゃったら　元も子もないんだよ
But at Chihatan Academy...
しかし我が知波単学園は…
Commander Nishizumi told us to hold this ridge.
西住隊長からこの陣地を守れって言われたでしょ
Commands are like rules.
命令ってのは規則と同じなの
But... But!
でもであります
Rules are meant to be obeyed.
規則は守るためにあるのよ
They will break through our line soon.
We will retreat and join the main force.
こちら　まもなく突破されます
退却　合流します
Come on, this way.
ほら　行くわよ
What are you doing?!
何をするでありますか?
いいからいいから
Just come with us.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
待たせたわね
We waited and waited
and now the black tea is cold.
待ちすぎて　紅茶が冷めてしまいましたわ
Well, sorry!
仕方ないでしょ
I thought we could break through more easily.
もっと簡単に敵を突破できると思ったのよ
We should have gone around them.
迂回すればよかったんですよ
Would you kindly pincer them now?
それより　早く挟撃態勢に入っていただける？
Sure thing!
任せなさい
Katyusha has arrived to save the day!
カチューシャたちが来たからには　もうおしまいよ
All tanks, aim for their flag tank!
全車輌でフラッグ車を狙って
Does she want to finish it here on the golf course?
То есть, исход битвы решится на этом поле для гольфа?
Yes, that would be ideal.
Да, хорошо есль всё получится
Nonna, Klara! Speak Japanese!
ノンナ　クラーラ
日本語で話しなさいよ
What is it?
Что?
We have the advantage by 40% in tanks and 95% in firepower.
車輌1.4倍
火力にあっては1.95倍　こちらが有利です
Our own reinforcements should also
arrive soon. We will move out, Katyusha.
私たちの援軍ももうすぐ到着するわ
行くわよ　カチューシャ
I give the orders here! Don't decide without me!
先に言わないで
命令するのは私なんだから
They're escaping!
逃げたぞ
Don't let them join the others! Finish them!
合流させるな
仕留めるぞ
What is that?
何だあれは?
They look like crabs.
カニっぽいね
They're Crusaders! Cruiser tanks
are fast and mobile, so be careful.
巡航戦車クルセイダー
足が速いから要注意だ
Cease firing!
砲撃中止
We're being pincered.
完全に挟まれました
All hope is lost!
もうダメだ
Now we can only die honorably!
こうなったら潔く散ろう
それが知波単魂
That is Chihatan spirit!
Stay calm!
早まるな
Commander Nishizumi,
what would you have us do?
西住隊長　いかがいたしますか？
We're at a disadvantage here.
ここで戦うのは不利です
Retreat.
撤退します
You'll show the enemy your rear?!
敵に後ろを　見せるのでありますか?
I don't want to retreat!
撤退なんてイヤであります
It's the rules.
規則だから
We can recover later.
あとで挽回しなって
We will descend from the hill
and try to divide their forces.
山を下ります
下り終えたら敵の戦力の分散につとめてください
Roger.
はい
Okay.
Understood.
かしこまりました
They wasted their best chance.
もう　せっかくのチャンスをフイにして
何やってんのよ
Human beings often fail.
人は失敗する生き物だからね
The important part is what you learn from it.
大切なのは　そこから　何かを学ぶってことさ
You can't hit me!
こっちこっち
Feel the spike of our 57mm gun!
57㎜砲のスパイク　受けてみよ
There!
そ～れ
Huh?
あれ？
We won't fall for that,
even if Black Forest Peak did.
黒森峰ならともかく
その手には乗りませんわ
They're fast. We will be surrounded.
速い　囲まれるぞ
Mallard Team, take point.
カモさん　先行してください
Accelerate and break through.
You're much heavier so you'll be fine.
加速して　一気に突っ切って
重量差があるから大丈夫
Roger!
はい
Hippo Team, follow them!
カバさんも続いてください
Understood.
心得た
Don't let them provoke you!
挑発に乗っちゃダメ
Follow the flag tank!
フラッグ車だけを追いなさい
They're not letting us divide them.
分断作戦に乗ってきませんね
Do you want to try a flag tank duel again?
もう一回相手のフラッグ車とタイマン張ります？
Too dangerous with so many others around.
周りが多いから危険かも
Mako, keep running away,
but allow them to follow you.
麻子さん　逃げてるけど　逃げきれない感じで走ってください
Okay.
分かった
Rabbit Team speaking.
こちらウサギチーム
Will you let us cover your back?
後ろのほう　任せてもらっていいですか
Please do. And be careful.
お願いします
気をつけてね
All right!
よっしゃー
The heavy-tank killer has arrived.
重戦車キラー参上
Good luck, Karina.
頑張って　桂利奈
Let's do this!
やったるぞー
Okay, the usual strategy!
よし　行くよ
いつものやつ
おりゃ
Shoot us if you want through!
悔しかったら撃ってみろー
Fear Ooarai!
大洗　なめんな
Fear us!
なめんな
They're so strong!
やっぱり強いよ
We'll be fine.
でも大丈夫
They can't shoot us right now.
これなら絶対　撃たれないし
Stop! Stop!
ストップストップ
えーと
Forward! Forward!
前進前進
Okay!
Hug them!
くっついて
You—
このぉぉぉー
This wasn't supposed to happen.
想定外
What now? What now?
どうするどうする？
What do we do?
どうしよう
If they fire...
このままじゃ
Saki is trying to say something!
さきが何か言おうとしてる
Butterfly.
ちょうちょ
You've fallen behind.
遅れてるわよ　ノンナどうしたの？
Nonna, what's keeping you?
It's nothing.
何でもありません
We will pass point OY-12 now.
これからＯＹ１２地点を通過します
Sic est.
As you will.
御意
Alles Klar
Alles klar!
Welcome.
お待たせー
Fire!
撃て
We hit them!
命中したぴよ
That was our first real hit!
リアルでは初撃破ぞなもし
We've gotten better!
うまくなったもんだも
When are we going to do a frontal attack?
突撃は　いつするんだろう？
What shall we do, Katyusha?
で　どうするの　カチューシャ
That's "Commander Katyusha"!
Also, we're going to advance, of course.
呼び捨てにしないで
前進に決まってるでしょ
I want to whittle them down until
they look like the filling in pirozhki!
こんなチマチマしたチビッこい連中　削って削って削り取って
ピロシキの中のお総菜にしたげるわ
Может ли быть такое, что 4ый зайдёт на Черчилль через зади?
Isn't the Panzer IV going to use this opportunity to surround the Churchill?
Yes, Miho might do that, Klara.
Думаю, да. Михо на такое способно, Кулара
Hey, you two! Speak Japanese!
ちょっとあなたたち　日本語で話しなさいよ
Nonna, you have the vanguard.
ノンナ　先鋒
Roger.
はい
Protect the flag tank, please.
Прикрой флаг, пожалуйста
Okay.
Поняла!
Rosehip.
ローズヒップIV号の狙いは私よ
The Panzer IV wants to hit me.
Think about that carefully
and decide what you need to do.
それをよく考えて　的確に行動しなさい
Rushing off seems ill conceived.
スピードを出すことに　夢中にならないで
I understand.
もちろんでこざいますわ
More again.
また来た
There they are! Blast them!
発見ですわ　やっつけますのよ
Don't overwork yourselves.
みんな　無理しないでね
Work at least a little, please!
会長は無理してください
They have a clear line of fire now.
直線になるぜよ
Retreat from the first block.
1ブロック後退
What's the point tank doing?
先頭車何をやってますの？
Lady Darjeeling's tea will be cold!
ダージリン様のお紅茶が冷めてしまいますわ
Really?
マジですの?
Vanilla, pull back!
バニラは後退
クランべリーは　わたくしとー緒に追いますわよ
Cranberry, chase them with me.
Beg your pardon!
ごめんあそばせ
We have to pull back soon.
そろそろ撤収するよ
Roger!
分かりました
The radio is damaged.
調子悪いなー
Sorry! I couldn't hear you!
すみません　聞き取りにくかったのですが
We're pulling back!
後退します
What?
はい？
Pull back.
後退です
P-U-L-L-B-A-C-K.
こ·う·た·い
A-T-T-A-C-K.
と·つ·げ·き
Gladly!
かしこまりでこさいます
Hm?
What?
Huh?
何？
Attack!
吶喊
Yes!
Oh, no!
あいた～
Sorry.
すみません　敢闘及びませんでした
Bravery wasn't enough.
Now!
来たぞ
Run!
逃げるにゃー
Captain Nishi!
西隊長
How dare they—
よくもよくも…
ストーップ
Stop!
Don't stop me!
止めないでください
I need to save face!
このままでは面目が立ちません
You'd lose face by falling here, too.
今ここでやられちゃったら　それこそ面目立たないよ
You can get your revenge later.
あとできっちり仕返しすればいいじゃない
You cannot run from the steeds of St. Gloriana!
聖グロ一の俊足からは　逃げられないんですのよ
Fire!
撃て
Stop.
停止
All right! Only one is left!
よーし　残り1輌
こちらレオポン
Leopon team speaking!
The OY defensive line has been broken!
ＯＹ防衛線崩壊しました
We also got taken out. Sorry.
あとやられちゃった
ごめんね
And so the tables are turned!
形勢逆転ですわー
Found you.
見ーつけた
Turn left.
左折してください
I won't let you get away.
Я не дам тебе уйти
That's how it's done!
やった
Again?
またかよ
I'm jealous it's always
your shop they blow up.
お前んとこばかりうらやましい
Let's finish this.
そろそろおしまいにしたげる
アヒル殿　どうしたら
Duck! What should we do?
Open areas are dangerous.
広い所は危ないね
Okay, so...
だったら…
You know, we have numbers right now...
おのれ　数的にはこちらが有利なのに
Fixed guns are so annoying
when you're being chased...
追いかけっこは　固定砲塔　不利よね
All right, let's do what Hina—
I mean, Carpaccio taught you.
よし　ひなちやん
もとい　力ルパッチョ直伝のアレをやるぞ
The CV 33 turn!
「CV33ターン」　別名「ナポリターン」
The Napoliturn!
Go, Oryou!
行け　おりょう
ぜよ
Okay!
Not the side!
ああ　そっちはダメぜよ
Mako, make a feint to the right and then turn left.
麻子さん　右にフェイント入れてから　左の道に入ってください
ほーい
Good work!
どーもでーす
This isn't fair! We're in a no-fire zone!
ずるいぞ
ここは発砲禁止区域だ
We know!
知ってまーす
Duck! Where now?
アヒル殿　このあとは？
I want to try a quick D. Just follow me.
Dクイック試してみるから
とりあえず　ついてきて
Roger, Duck!
了解であります　アヒル殿
Could you use my name, please?
「アヒル殿」ってなんかやだなー
Anteater will arrive at the target location soon.
アリクイ目標地点に　もうすぐ到着だぴょん
We're ready.
こちら準備ＯＫ
Are we doing this again?
またこんな役か
It's easy, so don't complain.
いいじゃん　楽で
Give them the Super Morals Attack!
行くわよ　スーパー風紀アタック
Okay!
はい
Wait some more!
まだねー　まだまだー
Fire!
撃て
We did it!
やったぜ　べイビー
Drive down from here.
ここを下ります
M'kay.
Are you sure?
大丈夫なの？
Mako can do it.
麻子さんなら大丈夫
Are you kidding me?
バッカじゃないの?
Mihosha is crazy!
ミホーシャ　ムチャしちゃって
Should we go around?
戻って回り込みますか？
Of course not! Down the stairs!
このまま進むに決まってるじゃない
I, Katyusha, can do
everything that Mihosha can do!
ミホーシャができることは
カチューシャにだってできるんだから
I know.
知ってます
As if we'd fall for that a second time!
バカめ　二度もだまされるか
Great!
よし
Good job!
お見事
I can't see anything.
見づらい…
I want a lower side mirror.
サイドアンダーミラー　欲しい…
Hey, we've found the flag tank.
おーい　フラッグ車見つけたよ
They were drinking tea on the roof.
のんきに外で　お茶飲んでた
Okay. We will meet you there.
分かりました　合流します
Darjeeling, draw them to your reliable allies.
ダージリン　頼れる同志の元におびき出して
I understand.
分かりました
"Reliable" allies?
頼れますか？
Don't worry. Look at the barrel.
大丈夫　砲身よく見て
Eat this!
これでも食らえ
Eat it!
食らえ
Hurry up and reload!
装填急ぐべ
Okay.
分がってら　装填完了だじゃ
Reloaded!
Turn the turret!
砲塔旋回
回るの　おっせーなー
It's so slow...
Hurry, hurry.
急げ急げ
Oh, my.
Turning the turret on such
a slope rolls the KV-2, huh?
KV-2　あの角度で回せばひっくり返りますよね
伏せて
Get down!
Aim for their flag tank!
フラッグ車だけを狙ってください
Only one...
初撃破…
Avenge us!
私たちの分も　頑張ってくださーい
You can do it, Kawashima!
河嶋先輩ガンバー
ぶっ殺せー
Slaughter them all!
Fight!
ファイトー
Hit them!
Stop!
危ない
Now we settle this.
どうやら決着がついたようね
What are you doing to do now?
I'll stop if you apologize.
どうする？
謝ったら　ここでやめたげてもいいけど
Stay close to the Churchill.
チャーチルから　離れないようにしてください
We're safer close to it.
くっついていたほうが安全です
The headliner has arrived.
真打ち参上ですわ
Only one...
初撃破…　ファイヤー
Feuer!
Katyusha, can I ask you to do something?
カチューシャ　お願いできる？
Fine.
仕方ないわね
Aqua World Ibaraki Prefecture Ooarai Aquarium
Another shell!
次
The Ooarai-Chihatan flag tank has been taken out.
大洗·知波単フラッグ車　走行不能
よって
聖グロリアーナ·プラウダの勝利
St. Gloriana-Pravda have won.
St. Gloriana Girls' Academy
Pravda High School
They lost.
負けちゃった
That they did.
そうだね
We should have taken part too.
やっぱり私たちも　出ればよかったのに
Why didn't we?
何で参加しなかったの？
I don't think we needed to.
出ればいいってもんでもないんじゃないかな
What? You think there was no meaning in this?
参加することに意義があるんじゃないの？
There are many times of importance in life.
人生には　大切な時が何度か訪れる
This simply wasn't one of them.
でも今はその時じゃない
Good work today, everyone.
本日は皆お疲れだった
Allow me to praise the victors first:
St. Gloriana and Pravda High School.
まずは勝利した聖グロリアーナ　およびプラウダ高校を称えたい
And I would also like to thank Chihatan, who graciously participated.
そして参加を快諾してくれた　知波単学園にも感謝の念を禁じ得ない
Sauna
A big thank you also goes to the Japanese Panzerfahren
Federation, who provided the referees for the match.
更には審判団を派遣してくれた　日本戦車道連盟
They were from the North Kanto branch, Ibaraki, Second Area.
北関東支部　茨城第2管区
And allow me to say that today I—
そして私事ながら　悲願の初撃破を…
Kawashima, keep it short.
河嶋　長い
That's all. Everyone, enjoy yourselves.
では以上
みんなゆっくりしていってくれ
Okay...
はーい
It may have been an exhibition match,
but the taste of victory is ever so sweet.
エキシビションとはいえ
勝利の味は　やはり格別ですね
Lady luck smiled upon us today.
勝負は時の運　ですわ
I'm getting out!
もう出る
You need to stay in the bath or
you won't become a good commander.
長く入らないと　いい隊長になれませんよ
Put your shoulders in the water and count to one hundred.
肩までつかって　100は数えてください
раз два три четыре
Count in Japanese!
日本語で数えなさいよ
I'm very sorry, Commander Nishizumi!
西住隊長　申し訳ありませんでした
If we hadn't rushed in to attack...
我々がはやって　突撃したりしなければ…
Don't worry.
いえ
I liked having you on my team.
ー緒にチームが組めてよかったです
I learned a lot.
いろいろ勉強になりました
What did you learn?
どの辺りが　勉強になったのですか？
Things about mentality.
精神とか
I see!
なるほど
The new term starts in a week, huh?
あと1週間で新学期ですね
I'm not done with my homework yet...
宿題まだ終わってな～い
I'll have to get up every morning again...
また毎朝起きねばならないのか
School should just disappear.
学校など　なくなってしまえばいいのに
We barely staved off having
the school abolished, you know?
廃校を免れたばかりなんですから
Kadotani Anzu, president of Ooarai Girls' Academy's student council:
大洗女子学園　生徒会長の角谷杏様
Please return to the school at once.
大至急　学園にお戻りください
I repeat.
繰り返します
Kadotani Anzu.
角谷杏様　大至急学園にお戻りください
Please return to the school at once.
What could that be?
何でしょう　急に
Well, I'm going back.
とにかく先に戻ってるわ
OOARAI TRANSPORT
Are they collecting their belongings?
皆さん　荷物をまとめてらっしゃるんでしょうか…？
Is getting rid of stuff
you don't need a big thing now?
断捨離ブームでも来たのかな
Dunno...
さあ…
Who did this?!
誰よ　勝手にこんなことするなんて
This couldn't be a prank, could it?
まさか落書きとかしてないよね
What does Keep Out mean, again?
あれ…？キープアウトってどういう意味だっけ？
Keep your weight.
体重をキープする
But your belly's sticking out!
してないじゃんアウトー
Don't be mean!
ひっどーい
そーいうこと　言ってる場合じゃないよ
We have bigger problems right now!
You there. Don't go in without permission.
君たち　勝手に入っては困るよ
Um, this is our school.
あの…　私たちはここの生徒です
You're no longer students.
もう君たちは生徒ではない
What do you mean?
どういうことですか?
Explain to them.
君から説明しておきたまえ
Prez!
会長?
What's going on, Prez?
どうしたんですか？会長
Prez!
会長？
Ooarai Girls' Academy...
大洗女子学園は　8月31日付けで廃校が決定した
was closed down August the 31st.
Consequently, the academy ship will be broken up for scrap.
廃校に基づき　学園艦は解体される
I thought we avoided that when we won the tournament...
戦車道大会で優勝したら
廃校は免れるって…
It seems they didn't guarantee that.
あれは確約ではなかったそうだ
What?!
何っ?
Apparently they were only willing to reexamine their decision.
存続を検討してもよいという意味で
正式に取り決めたわけではないそうだ
But...
そんな…
But this is too sudden!
それにしても急すぎます
Yeah!
そうです
And wasn't the school supposed to close at the end of March?
廃校にしろ　もともとは3月末のはずじゃ
Their reexamination led them to believe that was too late.
検討した結果　3月末では遅いという結論に至ったそうだ
That's so cruel!
なぁんで繰り上がるんですか
Then what did we fight for?
じゃあ　私たちの戦いは何だったんですか
We thought it was all to keep the school open...
学校がなくならないために頑張ったのに…
I can't accept this!
なっとくできーん
We're rebelling!
われわれは　ていこーする
何をする気?
We're doing what?
Let's occupy the school!
がっこーに　たてこもるぅー
戦艦バウンティ号の反乱だな
Mutiny on the Bounty!
Potemkin! Potemkin!
The Cannery Boat!
蟹工船…
The Caine Mutiny!
ケイン号の反乱
That one's fictitious!
それはフィクションだろ
I'm sorry, but the school really is closed now.
残念だが本当に廃校なんだ
If we resist, all the people that used to be employed on the ship won't receive a new appointment.
我々が抵抗すれば
艦内にいるー般の人たちの再就職はあっせんしない
They'd all be dismissed.
全員解雇にすると言われた
That's so cruel!
ひどすぎる…
Momo!
桃ちゃん
So what's going to happen? Is there going to be no Public Morals Committee anymore?
じゃあ　何？
学校がなくなるってことは　私たち風紀委員じゃなくなるわけ?
That's your problem?
そこか
It's an important job!
大切なことじゃない
There won't be any clubs...
じゃあ部活もなくなるし…
We'll never be able to revive the volleyball club!
バレー部　永久に復活できないです1
So the Automobile Club is also dissolved?
自動車部解散か?
I wanted to enter the Academy Ship Grand Prix...
学園艦GPの夢が…
We won't be first-years anymore?
私たちもー年生じゃなくなるの？
What are we going to be?
一年じゃなくなったら　どうなるの？
A real slacker...
リアルニート…
A poor and masterless samurai...
素浪人か…
Let us run away before our fiefdom disappears!
藩がなくなる前に脱藩しよう
It's already gone.
もうなくなってるだろ
Be quiet.
みんな静かに
Calm down and do what I tell you, please.
今は落ち着いて指示に従ってくれ
Are you okay with this, Prez?
会長は…
それでいいんですか
You heard her, didn't you? Everyone?
みんな　聞こえたよね
I'm sorry, but would those staying in the dorms please go there?
申し訳ないけど
寮の人は寮へ戻って
Those staying with their families, please go home.
自宅の人も家族の方と引っ越しの準備をしてください
Pack your belongings to move elsewhere.
Um...
あの…
What's going to happen to the tanks?
戦車はどうなるんですか？
The Ministry will take them.
すべて文科省預かりとなる
They're even taking our tanks?
戦車まで取り上げられてしまうんですか？
But...
そんな…
I'm sorry...
すまない…
I never thought I'd have to say goodbye to our school like this.
こんな形で　この学校と別れることになるなんて　思わなかったね
We don't need the documents for resolutions and the budget anymore, huh?
もう　決議案や予算案の書類…
いらないのかな？
Take everything you can.
できるだけ持っていくぞ
This is... our history.
これは我々の…　歴史だからな
I'm taking this chair with me.
この椅子も持っていくからな
Come on, get in.
ほら　入って
I wasn't responsible for them, you know?
私　生き物係じゃないんだけどな
I don't like dealing with animals...
生き物苦手だし
You'll get used to them.
慣れるよ
We can't leave them here.
やっば置いてけないもんね　この子たち
We'll never be able to revive the volleyball club, huh?
バレー部　もう永遠に復活できないんだね…
The school is going to disappear...
学校がなくなっちゃうんじゃ…
Let's play volleyball until the end!
最後にやろっか　バレー
Okay!
はい
Every morning we cracked down on the tardies for them.
毎朝毎朝学校のために　遅刻を取り締まってきたのに…
What should we live for now?
私たち　これから何を生きがいにすれしざいいの？
Do you want to take the school nameplate with us?
校門持ってく？
それいいわね
That sounds good!
I was kidding.
本気じゃないから
いた…
What are you doing?!
何してんのよ
Sorry...
すみませーん
Wait!
This'll be the last time we drive along here.
ここを走るのも最後か
Let's have fun and not mope.
しんみりするな　飛ばすぞ
Pedal to the metal!
走り納めだな
It's the last time. Let's really drift!
最後に思いっきり　ドリフトしてやる
As much as we want.
思う存分やんな
All hands abandon ship, huh?
総員退艦か…
I feel like we're being exiled to Kudoyama.
九度山へ蟄居のようだ
[Nekonya]
We can always talk, even if
we're a long way apart.
[Piyotan
[Momoga]
At night, yeah.
It's not going to be so bad.
Momoga has declared war on you.
Piyotan has declared war on you.
No!
もう　ダメだ
We'll be fish out of water!
陸に上がったらこの店は…
We'll be fine.
大丈夫よ
Right, Yukari?
優花里もね
Yeah...
What? Your school?
お嬢の学校が?
They're putting us on standby until
they've split us between our new schools.
転校先の振り分けが決まるまで　しばらく待機になるらしいの
Please come back to us, then.
でしたらぜひ　お戻りになってください
I don't want to be the only one missing.
わたくしだけ戻るわけにはいきません
Also... flowers can bloom anywhere
それに…　どこでも花は咲けるわ
as long as the heart has faith.
心がしおれないかぎり
I put the sheets here, okay?
いい？寝具はここにまとめといたからね
せっかくまとめたのに
They were all packed up!
I need the pillow I'm used to.
枕　変わると眠れないんだ
But you can sleep anywhere...
どこでも寝てるじゃん
The sleep is better quality.
眠りの質が違う
That's all now...
これで全部
Tomorrow we drop our belongings off and leave the ship, huh?
明日の朝には荷物を残して退艦…
You've come, Commander!
やっぱり隊長も
The others are already here.
みんな来てますよ
It's not much, but it did what it could.
ちっちゃい体で頑張ったよな
We haven't known each
other for long, but thank you.
短い間だったけど　本当にありがとう
Your shot when we fought Saunders was great.
お前のサンダース戦でのー撃は　すごかった
You did well against Pravda too.
プラウダ戦もよかったぞ
Miho, there you are.
みぽりんいたー
We tried to find you at your room,
お部屋まで行ったんですが…
but you must have left already.
こちらに向かわれた　あとだったんですね
Everyone has come here, huh?
皆さんもおそろいみたいで…
Mako, do you want to sleep here?
麻子さん　ここで寝るつもりなの？
Yeah...
Because...
もう　お別れかもしれないからな
this might be the last time I can.
Saunders U...
サンダース大付属の…
C-5Mスーパーギャラクシーです
has sent a C-5M Super Galaxy!
Saunders will keep our tanks for us.
サンダースで　うちの戦車を預かってくれるそうだ
Will that work out?
大丈夫なんですか?
We submitted lost equipment
forms to the ministry.
紛失したという書類を作ったわ
Now they won't be scrapped.
これでみんな処分されずにすむね
Hey there.
お待たせ
They're being a real pain about this, huh?
まったく世話をかけさせるわね
Thanks a bunch!
サンキューサンキュー
Don't sweat it!
こんなのお安い御用よ
All right, everyone! Hurry up!
さぁみんな　ハリーアップ
Okay!
はい
All tanks onboard.
確かに預かったわ
Tell me where you want them
once they've moved you.
移動先が分かったら連絡を頂戴
I will! Thank you!
はい
ありがとうごさいます
We'll get you your tanks.
届けてあげるわ
Will they be okay?
大丈夫でしょうか
The tanks must be heavy.
重そうだが飛べるのか？
Hang in there.
頑張って
よかった
Thank God...
学校は守れなかったけど
We couldn't protect our school,
but at least we could protect our tanks.
戦車は守ることができました
Yeah...
Thank You!
Ooarai Girls' Academy
Long Live Panzerfahren
全員そろってるな
Everyone is present, right?
Yes.
はい…
It's leaving port.
出港してしまうんですね
Do we have to say goodbye now?
これでお別れなんですか
Farewell.
さらば
This is harder than splitting up
with your boyfriend.
こんなの　彼氏と別れるよりつらいよ
You've never had one.
別れたこともないのに？
Don't leave!
行かないでぇー
Don't cry when it leaves!
笑って見送ろうよぉ～
Thank you!
ありがとう
げんきでねえ
I hope you'll be well!
さよおなら
Goodbye!
さぁよぉなぁらぁ～
The busses are splitting up further and further...
だんだんバスが分かれていくね
生徒の人数が多いから
We had a lot of students, so they're dividing us up by divisions to lodge them apart from each other.
みんな学科ごとに分かれて　宿泊するそうです
At least all the Panzerfahren girls are together.
戦車道を取ってる人は皆　固まってるみたいですけど…
Let's have some snacks!
とりあえすお菓子食べよ
Let's eat them together.
みんなで頂きましょう
Okay.
Until we've been distributed across schools, we will stay here on standby.
転校の振り分けが完了するまで　ひとまずここで待機となりま～す
We've allocated each class a classroom here.
クラス別に教室が割り当ててある
Bring your belongings there now.
速やかに移動しろ
はーい
Are you okay, Momo?
桃ちゃん　大丈夫？
We are the ones that need
to be dependable now.
こういう時こそ　我々がしっかりしなければ
I also believe the Prez will hatch a plan.
それにきっと　会長がなんとかしてくれる…はずだ
私たち同じ部屋だよ
Leave it to me!
私に任せてください
We have all sorts of rations to cook with.
レーションも各種ありますから　ちょっと待っててくださいね
Just wait a little.
She seems so upbeat.
なんかイキイキしてるよ…
She's indomitable.
たくましい
I wish I had her strength.
見習いたいです
We're no longer at sea.
もう海の上じゃないんだね
I can't hear the waves.
波の音も聞こえないし
I can't smell the salt.
潮の香りもあまりしません
The mountains aren't so bad.
いいじゃん　山も　緑がいっぱいあって
Look at all these plants.
I guess...
まぁ　そうだが…
They brought them to us like they promised!
約束どおり　運んできてくれました
よかった…
Thank the Heavens...
Seeing our tanks makes me so much happier.
戦車を見るとほっとする…
Got you your tanks!
ちゃんと届けたわよ
Thank you!
ありがとうこざいます
You'll have to make this up to us.
この借りは高くつくわよ
この借りを返すために　戦車道を続けなさい
Don't stop doing Panzerfahren. That's how you can repay us.
We're going to knock you all silly the next time we battle.
今度はあたしたちがコテンパンにするんだから
Okay!
はい
We can live here for the time being.
とりあえず当面は　ここで生活できそうだな
Will we really be okay here?
いいんですか　このままここにいて
This place is old and on land, but we can just act like we did on the ship.
こんな場所だが
学園艦にいる時と同じように
朝は出席を取って　全員無事なのを確認するように
We can take attendance in the morning and make sure everyone is fine.
Okay.
分かりました
Where's the Public Morals Committee?
そういえば風紀委員はどうした？
Hey!
おい　風紀委員のくせに　だらしないぞ
You're the Public Morals Committee! Get your act together!
きちんとしろ
Hey, our school is gone and stuff. What's even the goddamn point?
もう学校もないのに
きちんとしたからって　どうなるっていうんですかぁ
Ain't one, right?
意味ないじゃないですか
No point for us to be here.
私たちがいる意味すら
Just act the part until we're all
distributed across new schools!
いいから全員の転校手続きが終わるまではちゃんとやれ
Everyone, assemble.
ぜんいん　しゅーごぉー
We have no school anymore,
so why do I have to get up in the morning?
学校なくなったんだから　朝起きなくてもいいんじゃないか
I heard they're taking attendance anyway.
出席は毎日取るんだって
Wash your face, Sodoko!
顔くらい洗え　そど子
Yeah, sure.
はいはい　どーせ私はそど子ですよ
Sodoko's a decent nickname...
Who's absent...?
出欠を取りまーす
Great, nobody.
全員いるわね
M'kay, have fun.
はい　終了
What a sloppy roll call.
なんてアバウトな出席の取り方なんでしょう
It's hot, but we need to practice!
暑いけど頑張ろう
I want to hear you!
声出していくぞ
はい　そーれっ
Okay!
Hah!
This is our chance to steel our bodies!
この機会に体を鍛え直そう…
Yes!
そうだね…
This is so hard...
頑張らなきゃ
まいりました
I can't win this.
I don't think so.
だろうな…
What're you fishing for?
何釣ってるの？
Anglerfish.
あんこう
Not going to happen.
無理だと思うよ
Oysters, then.
じゃ　岩ガキ
That's even less likely.
もっと無理だと思うよ
Hm, goby.
じゃ　ハゼ
This is good practice!
いい練習になるな
Keep it under control.
ほどほどにね
I never thought I'd drive the tank down to the supermarket.
まさかコンビニに　戦車で行くことになるなんて
Good thing we got the tank driver's license.
戦車の免許が役に立ったな
At least open your eyes when you take a photo for your driver's license!
免許の写真くらい　目パッチリ開けて撮りなよ
I'll use mine for marriage interviews!
あたしのなんて　お見合い写真にも使えるよ
You really put a lot into that picture.
ムダに気合入ってますね
There's a bus from the supermarket to Ibaraki, right?
コンビニ前から　茨城町方面のバスが出てましたよね
I need to look at the schedule.
時間調べとかないと
Why?
何でー？
I have to go home to my parents, at least for a day or so.
ー度親の所に戻るんです
The school transfer form needs my guardians' seal on it.
転校手続きの書類に　親のハンコがいるみたいで
Guardians...
保護者…
You'll have to go home to Grandma.
おばあのとこに行かなきゃね
What a drag.
面倒だな　また説教されるだろうし…
She'll preach to me again.
I have to go home too.
あたしもうちに戻んなきゃ
What about you, Miho?
みほさんは？
Do you want us to come with you?
ー緒に行こうか？
I want to know how the Nishizumi school lives.
西住流家元も見てみたいですし
ううん　大丈夫　ー人で帰れる
It's okay. I can make it alone.
I see.
そうですか…
You can visit me there some other time.
また今度遊びに来てね
Thanks!
はい
I'm going home tomorrow.
わたくしは明日家に帰ります
I should probably do that too.
わたしもそうしょうかな
I will—
私も
Stop!
止まってください
そのままバックして
Back up a little.
どうしたんですか？
What's up?
Tear Museum
E
H
W
Left In 500m
X
Why didn't I know this place existed?!
知らなかった　こんなとこがあるなんて
I've never seen you so excited.
今まででー番テンション上がってるよ
I'll do it, I swear I will
やってやる　やってやる　やってやるぜ
Hey, everyone! Thanks for coming!
おう　よく来やがったなお前たち
I'll be with you!
I tear those jerks up good
おいらが相手してやろう
イヤなあいつをボコボコに
I'll tear you up!
ボコボコにしてやるぜ
It's the real Tearbear! He's so cute!
生ボコだー　かわいー
Fights are meant to be picked
ケンカは売るもの　堂々と
What are you doing? Stop it?
なにをする　やめろ
We're not doing anything.
何もしてないわよ
I'll turn 'round and dress 'em down
肩に風きり　啖呵きる
You did me in good.
やられた
But remember!
覚えてろよ
It's not a problem if you lose in life
人生　負けてもいいんだぜ
だからなにもしてないって
We're not doing anything.
He's so weak for how tough he acts.
イキが割に弱い
Yes! He's the Tearbear!
それがボコだから
Just keep dreaming of victory
いつか勝てると夢を見て
Like the Italian Tenth Army, huh...
イタリア軍の第十軍みたいですね
なんかわたくしたちの他にお客さんいないみたいなんですけど…
It looks like we're the only visitors...
Come on, come on, come on, you can do this!
Come on Come on,
Come on, You can this!
Just endure it when they tear at you
ボコり　ボコられ　生きていけ
おう　よく来やがったな
イッツ・ア・ボコワールド…
"It's a torn world."
"Dawn of the torn."
ボコーテッドマンション…
勝ってやる　勝ってやる　勝ってやるぜ
I'll win, I swear I will
スペイスボコンテン
"Torn in space."
Hey, be careful who you bump into!
おい　今ぶつかったぞ　気をつけろ
One day I'll tear them apart
強いあいつをボコボコに
Let's trash this moron.
生意気で　やっちまえ
All I have is my spirit
あるのはこれだけ　生意気
This gonna be fun.
You're gonna eat dirt so hard.
おもしれえ　返り討ちにしてやらー
and my fearless perseverance
You're all talk, aren't ya?
根性据えて　根性よく
口ほどにもないやつめ
Everyone, give me strength!
みんな　おいらに力をくれー
It's fine if you lose your battles
勝負は　負けてもいいからさ
Hang in there, Tearbear!
ボコ　頑張れ
I need strength!
もっと力を
Just don't lose your fighting spirit
You can do it!
頑張れ
戦うココロなくすなよ
More!
もっとだ
You can—
You can do it, Tearbear!
頑張れ　ボコー
Come on, come on, come on, you can do this!
You can do it, Tearbear!
頑張れ　ボコー
Come on Come on,
Tearbear, hang in there!
ボコ頑張れ
Come on You can this!
You can do it!
ボコさん　頑張って
You can do it, Tearbear!
ボコ　いけー
Just endure it when they tear at you
ボコり　ボコられ　生きていけ
Tearbear, hang in there!
ファイトー
来た来た来た
I'm back!
You cheered me on
and now I have more power!
皆の応援が　おいらのパワーになったぜ
ありがとうよ
Thank you!
お前らまとめて　やってやらー
I'm gonna bash your skulls in!
That all?
Hey, hey!
包帯　バンソコ　勲章さ
Bandages and plasters are my medals
What the hell?
なにこれ
So he gets torn up anyway, huh?
結局はボコボコにされるんですか
I won't run away
He's Tearbear!
それがボコだから
オレは絶対逃げないぜ
また負けた
I lost again.
Come on, come on, come on, you can do this!
I'll make it one day!
Come on Come on,
次は頑張るぞ
Come on, You can this!
すごく頑張ってたね　ボコ
Tearbear really tried, didn't he?
I'll endure it when they tear at me
ボコり　ボコられ　生きていく
Really...?
そう？
ONE LEFT!
SUPER RARE
Tearbear
あ　残り一つだって
Only one is left!
That's how they trick you...
そういう手だから
Come on, come on, come on, you can do this!
Come on Come on,
ONE LEFT!
SUPER RARE
Tearbear
He's cute, though.
だも可愛いし
Come on, You can this!
I'll endure it when they tear at me
あっ　いいのいいの
ボコり　ボコられ　生きていく
You can have it.
I'll come here again.
私はまた来るから
せっかくみぽりんが譲ってあげたのに
You gave it to her and
she didn't even say thank you...
お礼も言わないなんて
I bet she's just shy.
きっと恥ずかしいだけだよ
Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology
Academy Ship Department
The decision is final.
The school will be closed.
廃校の件は決定しているんです
I recall your promise that the school
would not be closed if we won the tournament.
ですが　優勝すれば廃校は免れるという約束をしたはずです
口約束は約束ではないでしょう
It was just a verbal promise.
判例では口約束も約束と認められています
Judicial precedent recognizes it as binding.
Articles 91 and 97 of the Civil Code
form the basis for this.
民法91条　97条等に記されています
I did all I could.
可能なかぎり善処したんです
Surely you understand.
ご理解ください
I see.
分かりました
Staff Room
Temporarily
Student Council Room
We don't have any bug bite medicine anymore.
虫刺されの薬がなくなりました
Okay. I'll order more.
分かった　すぐ手配する
We won't have enough rice for lunch.
給食用のお米が足りません
Okay. I'll have the farmers bring more.
分かった　農家の方に手配してもらう
The light bulb in the hallway ran out.
廊下の電球が切れました
電気屋さんに頼んでおく
I'll buy one from an appliance store.
大変です　風紀委員の３人が地元の生徒とケンカしてます
I need some help! The Public Morals Committee is brawling with some local kids.
I'll go and talk to a mediator.
ちょっとケンカの仲裁に行ってくる
All right.
了解
What's up?
何だ？
You're trying your best...
桃ちゃん　頑張ってるなぁ　って
I was afraid you'd cry.
もっと泣き叫ぶかと思ったのに
"Our school! Abolished!
What are we going to do, Yuzu?"
「廃校だぁ　もうおしまいだよ　柚子ちゃん」って
I don't have time for that!
そんな暇はない
Now is the time to buckle down!
今頑張らねば　いつ頑張るというのだ
そうだよね…
Yup.
I wonder where the Prez is.
会長は　どこ行っちゃったんだろうね
I'm sure she's making her plans.
会長には会長のお考えがあるはずだ
Japanese Panzerfahren Federation
Not even we can easily change
the finalized decisions of the Ministry.
文科省がー旦決定したことは
我々にもそう簡単には覆せないしなぁ…
Because such a change
would reflect badly on them?
向こうのメンツが立たないということですか？
Mostly, yes...
そういうことになるかな…
If we are talking about appearances,
メンツということであれば
then won't it reflect badly
on the Panzerfahren Federation
優勝するほど力のある学校をみすみす廃校にしては
if a school powerful enough to win
the tournament is closed down mere weeks later?
それこそ　戦車道連盟のメンツが立ちません
Miss Chouno, you're a member of
the Federation's Promotion Committee, right?
蝶野君も連盟の強化委員のー人だろう？
But Chairman, strengthening
Panzerfahren is government policy.
ですが理事長
戦車道に力を入れるという　国の方針とも矛盾しますし
Girls Who Protected Their School With Panzerfahren Betrayed
This contradiction will hurt our prestige.
何よりもイメージが下がります
We fought believing that a victory
would stave off the closure of our school.
私たちは優勝すれば廃校が撤回されると信じて戦ったんです
I will not accept that the path
we believed in was never possible.
信じた道が「実は最初からなかった」と言われ
引き下がるわけにはいきません
Well, we will host the World Cup in two years.
The Ministry must be swamped.
しかし今文科省は2年後に開催される
世界大会のことで頭がいっぱいだからなぁ
They're trying hard to launch
a professional league to promote it.
誘致するためにプロリーグを発足させようとしているくらいだから
They won't be swayed by a little bad press.
取り付く島がないよ
A professional league?
That sounds promising.
プロリーグ　それですね
Time for a pivot turn.
ここは　超信地旋回でいきましょう
Beniharuka
Sweet Potatoes
Miho.
みほ
Sis...
お姉ちやん…
Welcome home.
おかえり
Are you sure?
いいの？
This is your home.
ここはお前の家だ
Don't be afraid to come here.
戻ってくるのに何の遠慮がある
Maho?
まほ？
Yes?
はい
You have a visitor?
お客様なの？
A friend from school.
学校の友人です
I see...
そう
What's wrong?
どうした？
Nothing has changed...
変わってない…
What about the form?
書類は？
Here.
これ
Wait here.
ちょっと待ってろ
Okay.
Miho.
みほ
Nishizumi   Shiho
えっ　お姉ちやん　そのサインとハンコは？
Maho!
Did you make this signature and the stamp?
本当に駅まででいいのか？
You're sure you only need a ride to the station?
Yeah. Thank you.
うん　ありがとう…
This is all as I remember it.
ここも昔のまま…
WIN
NO WIN
Beniharuka
Sweet Potatoes
A present
from my friend.
Maho
My lady.
家元
Beniharuka
Sweet Potatoes
Miss Chouno has arrived.
蝶野様がお見えです
分かっている
I know.
If Ooarai Girls' Academy does not
participate in the tournament next year,
来年の大会に　大洗女子学園が出てこなければ…
Black Forest Peak will not be able to crush them.
黒森峰がたたき潰すことが　できなくなるわね
All professionals saw their talents nurtured when they were young.
若手の育成なくして　プロ選手の育成はなしえません
Our difference in perception
これだけ考えの隔たりがあっては
may make it infeasible for me to work as head of the league establishment committee.
プロリーグ設置委員会の委員長をわたくしが務めるのは難しいかと
Well, that would be...
いやそれは…
If the professional league is not established by the end of this fiscal year,
今年度中に　プロリーグを設立しないと
then it will not effectively promote the Panzerfahren world cup. Surely you understand this.
戦車道大会の誘致ができなくなってしまうのは
先生もご存じでしょう
It seems to me that closing the winning school actively damages the sport's promotion.
優勝した学校を廃校にするのは
文科省が掲げる　スポーツ振興の理念に反するのでは？
But it was just a fluke...
しかしまぐれで　優勝した学校ですから…
There are no flukes in Panzerfahren. Only skill.
戦車道にまぐれなし
あるのは実力のみ
What must be done so that you understand?
どうしたら認めていただけますか
Well, if they win against
the University All-Stars team...
まぁ　大学強化選手に勝ちでもしたら…
We accept.
分かりました
You will reinstate our school if we win, right?
勝ったら廃校を撤回してもらえますね
Let's sign a memorandum
of understanding right here.
今ここで
覚書を交わしてください
I've heard verbal promises
are not real promises.
うわさでは口約束は　約束ではないようですからね
Congratulations on being
the new family head.
家元襲名　おめでとうごさいます
Thank you.
ありがとうこさいます
I hope I have your forbearance in this matter, Lady Shimada.
ここはぜひ大学強化チームの責任者である島田流家元にも
You are responsible for the University All-Stars team.
ご了承を頂きたいと思いまして
You do.
分かりました
We are not going to
hand you the victory, however.
こちらもやるからには　手加減はいたしません
All clear.
状況終了
It is obvious why they call her style a chameleon.
さすが変幻自在の戦術
She's often compared to the ninjas.
二ンジャ戦法と呼ばれるだけあるわ
This is the future of Panzerfahren right here:
「日本戦車道ここに在り」と知らしめた
the successor to the Shimada school.
島田流戦車道の後継者
It's running now.
始まってる…
I'm glad I'm recording it.
よかった　録画しておいて…
Commander!
隊長　何かお約束でも？
Do you have an appointment?
Don't worry about it.
気にする必要はない
There has been a call
from home for you earlier.
先ほど　家元からお電話があったそうです
From Mother?
母上から？
Give them a thorough beating.
徹底的にたたきのめしなさい
May the proud name
Nishizumi descend to mortality.
西住流の名が地に落ちるように
I understand what I must do.
試合の件は承知しました
I have something I would like to ask of you as well.
こちらにもお願いしたいことが
Yes?
お願い？
I would like us to sponsor
the Tearbear museum if I win.
私が勝ったら　ボコミュージアムのスポンサーになってほしいんだけど
I think they will have to close otherwise.
このままでは　たぶん廃館になっちゃうの
Very well.
しょうがないわね
Thank you, Mother.
お母様　ありがとう
You'll be fine.
大丈夫　私が助けてあげるからね
I will save you.
I'm back.
ただいま
Prez!
会長
Please assemble for a special announcement.
非常呼集　非常呼集
The president has returned to ship.
会長が帰還されました
All Panzerfahren members
are to assemble immediately.
戦車道受講者は直ちに講堂へ集合
All right.
とにかく　行くにゃ
繰り返します
Let's go!
非常呼集　非常呼集
会長が帰還されました
What's that weird sound in the background?
戦車道受講者は直ちに講堂へ集合
ねえ　後ろで変な声聞こえない？
It's so creepy.
こわーい
I repeat.
繰り返します　非常呼集　非常呼集
Roll call for a special announcement.
桃ちゃん　静かに
Momo, be a little more quiet.
Everyone's here!
全員集まったな
Mallard team is not here yet.
カモさんチームが来てませーん
What?
何？
Where are you going?
どこ行くの？
Gathering the tardies.
遅刻を取り締まってくる
What're you doing?
何してる？
What's it to you?
関係ないでしょ
We're assembling.
集合だ
Not coming.
いやだ
Come with me.
いいから来い
何すんのよ　離しなさいよ
Stop it! Let go!
Leave us alone!
私たちのことなんか　ほっといてよ
We need you to look after our behavior!
そど子がいないと　風紀が乱れるだろ
I also miss you a little.
それにちょっと寂しい
私たちは寂しくないんだから
We don't miss you!
That's not what it's for...
それはやめてよ…
Everyone, we have a match coming up.
みんな　試合が決まった
A match?!
試合？
Against the University All-Stars.
大学強化チームとだ
If we win against them,
大学強化チームとの試合で勝てば
our school will reopen.
今度こそ廃校は撤回される
This is a signed pledge from
the director of the Ministry.
文科省局長から　念書も取ってきた
It's also signed by the heads of the National, University,
戦車道連盟
大学戦車道連盟
and High School Panzerfahren Federations.
高校戦車道連盟の承認ももらった
You're amazing!
さすが会長
You were working for us all the time.
やっぱりちゃんと動いてくれてたんですね
You're not hiding anything
from us this time, right?
会長　もう隠していることは　ないですよね
Nope!
ない
They will really reopen it if we win, right?
勝ったら本当に　廃校撤回なんですね
That's right!
そうだ
I know this is a tall order.
無理な戦いということは　分かっている
But we will win...
だが　必ず勝って
and return to Ooarai,
みんなで大洗に…
our academy ship!
学園艦に帰ろう
やるぜよ
Let's do this!
Yes!
All right!
よっしゃー
Let's do our best.
頑張りましょう
Be more excited!
あんたも「おう」とか言いなさいよ
Sure, sure.
Lady Nishizumi.
西住殿…
They crushed the office workers' team?
Dazzling Victory!
University All-Stars Crush Corporate Team
Alice Shimada
Talent Beats Experience
社会人を破ったチーム?
They must be nearly invincible!
いくら何でも無理ですよ
Yeah, I know they are.
無理は承知だよ
Nishizumi, what do you think?
西住　どう思う？
I think I've seen their commander before...
選抜チームの隊長　どこかで見た気が…
They call her a genius. She skipped grades too.
University All-Stars Crush Corporate Team
Alice Shimada
Talent Beats Experience
天才少女って言われてるらしいな　飛び級したとか
She's the daughter of the head
of the Shimada family.
島田流家元の娘なんだよね
This is also a duel between the schools of Nishizumi and Shimada.
つまりこの試合は島田流対西住流の対決でもあるんだな
How many tanks will they field?
で相手は何輌出してくるんですか？
Thirty.
30輌
That's hopeless!
もうダメだ
Tell us it's hopeless, Nishizumi!
西住からも　勝つのは無理だと伝えてくれ
We can't win with what we have right now.
確かに今の状況では勝てません
But I think getting even these terms must have been tough.
ですがこの条件を取り付けるのも　大変だったと思うんです
Tanks can carve a path where nothing else can.
普通は無理でも　戦車に通れない道はありません
They even advance through pyroclastic flow.
戦車は火砕流の中だって　進むんです
Let's approach this with
the mentality that it can be done.
困難な道ですが　勝てる手を考えましょう
Okay.
はい
Roger.
分かりました
A battle of annihilation? What's that again?
殲滅戦って何だったっけ？
You have to take out all enemy tanks to win.
相手の車輌を全部やっつけたほうが勝つんだよ
I see.
そうなんだ
We already had to face their thirty tanks with eight,
あの　30輌に対して8輌で　その上突然殲滅戦っていうのは…
and now you're making it a battle of annihilation...
Battles of annihilation will be
the standard match mode in the pro league,
予定されるプロリーグでは　殲滅戦が基本ルールになっていますので
so we want to expand their use now.
それに合わせていただきたい
They told me the world cup will also be battles of annihilation...
もう大会準備は　殲滅戦で進めてるんだって
If you wish to withdraw, please let us know soon.
辞退するなら　早めに申し出るように
I'm sorry so much rests on you.
苦労かけるね
It's okay.
いえ…
What are we going to do tomorrow?
どうする？明日の試合
Should we withdraw?
辞退するという選択肢も…
Of course not.
それはありません
Nothing ventured, nothing gained.
退いたら道はなくなります
Yep.
It's going to be tough.
厳しい戦いになるな
Our battles always are.
私たちの戦いはいつもそうです
But...
でも…
Miho!
みぽりーん
We're all together in this.
みんながいますから…
The long sobs
「秋の日の　ヴィオロンのためいきの
Of the autumn violins
Wound my heart
ひたぶるに身にしみて　うら悲し
With a bleak languor
Let us drink together in the north
北の地にて飲みかわすべし」
Hot black tea, no doubt.
熱い紅茶ですね
I've never had black tea.
紅茶って　飲んだことないんだよな
A tea party sounds fun.
お茶会　楽しそうだよ
I cannot approve of a carpe diem mentality.
刹那主義には賛同できないね
We have to draw them into
the hills and divide their forces.
相手を山岳地帯におびき寄せて　分散させて
Then we can pick them apart and perhaps win.
各個撃破できれば　勝機は見えるはず
But she's more experienced and talented than I am...
でも　相手は経験も実力も上…
もしかすると今度ばかりは…
Are we really going to...
The match between Ooarai Girls' Academy and the University All-Stars will begin.
では　これより　大洗女子学園対大学選抜チームの試合を行います
Greet.
礼
Tha—
よろしく…
Hold it!
待ったーっ
Sis?
お姉ちゃん
Nishizumi Maho, from Ooarai Girls' Academy.
大洗女子学園　西住まほ
Itsumi Erika, same school.
同じく　逸見エリカ
The following eighteen students will participate in the match.
以下18名　試合に参戦する
The paperwork for a short-term school transfer has all been approved.
短期転校の手続きは済ませてきた
We have permission from
the Panzerfahren Federation as well.
戦車道連盟の許可も取り付けてある
Thank you, Sis...
お姉ちゃん　ありがとう
Transferring the tanks as well is against the rules!
戦車まで持ってくるのは反則だ
I'm sure they're all their personal property.
皆　私物なんじゃないですかぁ　私物がダメってルールありましたっけ
Everyone is free to bring their personal property, I believe.
This is abuse of the rules!
卑怯だぞ
We've transferred in as well!
私たちも転校してきたわよ
We're teammates now.
今からチームメイトだから　覚悟なさい
Buckle up!
Saunders is here!
サンダースが来た
I didn't expect Black Forest Peak and Saunders to fight with us...
黒森峰とサンダースの皆さんが加わってくれるなんて
We're getting so much stronger!
鬼に金棒ね
And more by the minute.
虎に翼
もう　一番乗り逃がしちゃったじゃない
We missed out on being first!
Please remind me who overslept.
お寝坊したのは誰ですか
Well, I'm not here because I want to be.
まあ　別に来たくて来たわけじゃないんだけどね
But you wanted to be first and show off.
でも一番乗りして　かっこういいとこ見せたかったんですよね
Stop nitpicking everything!
いちいちうるさいわね
Shall I wear my usual tank jacket?
やっぱり試合には　いつものタンクジャケットで挑みますか
Why did we change into
their school uniform, then?
じゃあ　何でわざわざ大洗の制服そろえたんですか
Everyone said they wanted to try them on.
みんな着てみたかったんだって
Gloriana and Pravda!
グロリアーナやブラウダの皆さんまで
Ladies of Ooarai!
大洗諸君
The duce has come from
the land of pasta and passion!
ノリと勢いとパスタの国からドゥーチェ参戦だ　恐れ入れ
Tremble in fear!
I'm glad we made it in time.
今度は間に合ってよかったっすね
Hippo team! Taka!
カバさんチームの貴ちゃーん　来たわよ
I'm here!
ひなちゃん
Hina!
うっ　カエサルだ
Call me Caesar...
Hello, everyone.
こんにちは　皆さん　継続高校から転校してきました
We've transferred in from Continuation High School.
You're still helping them after what you said.
なんだかんだ言って助けてあげるんだね
I've merely been blown here on the wind.
違う　風と一緒に流れてきたのさ
Hello!
お待たせしました　昨日の敵は今日の盟友
Yesterday's enemy is today's ally!
We've come with twenty-two brave, iron lions!
勇敢なる鉄獅子22輌推参であります
We told you that we needed
twenty-two tanks in total.
増援は私たち全部で22輌だって言ったでしょう
You were supposed to bring six tanks.
あなたのところは6輌
I'm sorry! What a misunderstanding!
すみません　心得違いをしておりました
Sixteen tanks, return to standby!
16輌は待機
We might be able to win!
これは勝てるかも
It's not against the rules to change the roster before the match?!
試合直前での選手増員はルール違反じゃないのか
The only ones who can object
are the opposing team.
異議を唱えられるのは相手チームだけです
We don't mind.
我々は構いません　受けて立ちます　試合を開始してください
We will face them.
Begin the match.
C
B
Team Composition
Pz IV, Churchill, Matilda, Crusader, BT-42,
I.
CV33, B1 bis, VK 45.01 (P), Type 3, Type 89
II.
Tiger, Tiger II, Panther 2x, T34-85 2x,
IS-2, KV-2, StuG III, Hetzer
M4, M4A1, Firefly, M3,
III.
Type 97 SHT 2x, Type 97 3x, Type 95
We'll split into three platoons as listed on the blackboard.
では　このとおり3個中隊の編成でいきたいと思います
Okay!
ＯＫ
Who will command the platoons?
中隊長は
Um, my sist—
それぞれ　お姉ちゃん…　西住まほ選手　ケイさん　それから私で
I mean, Nishizumi Maho, Kei, and I will each command one.
西側ばかりじゃない
You're all from the west.
Are you unhappy?
ご不満？
Do you want to be commander?
隊長　やりたいんですか
Of course I do!
私がやらなくて　どうするのよ
I guess next time is fine.
まあ　今度でいいけど
Katyusha, please be the deputy commander.
カチューシャさんは副隊長をお願いします
You'll let me? All right, I'll do you the favor.
あっそう　仕方ないわね　やってあげるわ
Darjeeling, Nishi. Please be
the other deputy commanders.
ダージリンさんと西さんも副隊長をお願いします
Very well.
よろしいわ
I shall do my very best!
誠心誠意　努力します
You're the army commander, right? Miho?
大隊長はみほだな
We're gonna follow you.
あなたについていくわよ
Commander, please name the platoons.
大隊長殿　部隊名の下知をお願いします
Uh... Okay.
じゃあ　西住まほチームがひまわり
Nishizumi Maho's platoon is called Sunflower.
Kei's platoon is Morning Glory.
ケイさんのところが　あさがお
I'll be Dandelion. Is that okay?
うちがたんぽぽでどうでしょう
I rather like that.
よろしいんじゃない
What's the plan going to be?
作戦はどうする
We need mobile warfare.
行進間射撃しかないんじゃないかしら
We have to keep moving and whittle them down.
常に動き続けて撃ち続けるのよ
Drive a wedge into them
with an infiltration assault!
楔を打ち込み　浸透突破でいくべきよ
This calls for the superior firepower doctrine.
優勢火力ドクトリンじゃない　1輌に対して10輌で攻撃ね
Attack one of their tanks with ten of yours.
We need a double envelopment!
二重包囲がいいわ　それで冬まで待って　冬将軍を味方につけましょう
Then we wait until winter
comes and fights on our side!
There's no time limit on annihilation battles.
殲滅戦は制限時間ないんだし
I've considered all manner of strategies,
but I believe we can only mount a frontal assault.
わたくし様々な可能性を鑑みましたが　ここは突撃するしかないかと
Can we boil some pasta first?
とりあえずパスタをゆでてから考えていいか
Frontal Assault
Winter
Pasta
Frontal Assault
You all said you would obey Miho.
みんなみほに従うと言っただろう
Frontal Assault
Miho.
みほ
Right.
ああ　はい
Sunflower will be the main force and Morning Glory and Dandelion will cover the flanks.
ひまわりチームを主力として　あさがおとたんぽぽが側面をかためてください
Stay close enough to support each other.
連携が取れる距離を保ちつつ　離れすぎないよう　注意してください
Okay.
Roger.
はい　ＯＫ
I have a very important question...
で　ここからが肝心なんだけど
What's the operation codename?
作戦名はどうする
We're attacking from three directions,
so it should be "Operation Three-Cheese Pizza".
三方向から攻めるんだから　三種のチーズピザ作戦
Operation Beef Stroganoff!
ビーフストロガノフ作戦がいいわ
It's amazing! It has onion and meat and sour cream!
玉ねぎと牛肉とサワークリームの取り合わせは最高よ
Let us call it Operation Fish and Chips with Vinegar.
フィッシュ＆チップス＆ビネガー作戦と名付けましょう
Operation Glühwein und Eisbein!
グリューワインとアイスバイン作戦
Operation Fried Chicken with Gravy!
フライドチキンステーキwithグレイビーソース作戦
Operation Anglerfish with Dried Potato and Clams!
あんこう干し芋ハマグリ作戦
会長まで乗らないでください
Don't be a fool too!
Let's take the middle ground
with Operation Sukiyaki.
間を取って　スキヤキ作戦はどうですか
Don't name the operation after your favorite food.
好きな食べ物と作戦は関係ないだろう
Then what do you suggest?
じゃあ　何がいいのよ
Operation Meistersinger von Nürnberg.
ニュルンベルクのマイスタージンガー作戦はどうだ　これは三幕からなるオペラで
It's a three-act opera—
Too long!
長い
Decide, Commander.
大隊長　決めてくれ
Okay...
じゃあ　「こっつん作戦」で
Operation Bumpy.
The plan is to push them back and go for a decisive blow.
相手を突きだして　「えいっ」て攻める作戦なので
That name completely lacks impact.
何それ　迫力ないわね
それでいこう
Let's go with it.
Bumpy! All right!
こっつんですか　なるほど
Sounds good.
いいんじゃない
All right. Dandelion will be on the right and Morning Glory on the left.
では右側面がたんぽぽ　左にあさがお　中央にひまわりでお願いします
Sunflower, take the center.
Roger.
はい
Begin Operation Bumpy!
こっつん作戦　開始します
Panzer vor!
パンツァーフォー
What would you have us do, Commander?
どうします　隊長
They may be only high school students, but they're experienced and talented.
高校生とはいえ　相手はかなりの戦力を有しています
We need to take out Pravda's
and Black Forest Peak's heavy tanks first.
まずはプラウダと黒森峰の重戦車を倒す
Azumi, Rumi.
アズミとルミの中隊は　私とともに
Your platoons and mine will slowly advance in a long phalanx.
広く長い一列横隊を形成して　ゆっくり前進
Beware of flanking attacks.
側面からの強襲に注意しろ
The recon tanks are to hold fire if at all possible.
偵察車は敵と遭遇しても攻撃をするな
Roger.
了解
All tanks, forward.
各車前進
Rumi, roger.
こちらルミ　了解
Azumi, understood. Advancing.
アズミ　了解しました　前進開始
Megumi speaking. I will attach
my platoon to yours, Commander.
メグミ　中隊を併進させます
The earliest we might make contact
with their force is in twenty minutes.
接触は早くて20分後
こちら大隊長車　相手の動きはまだ確認できていません　慎重に行動してください
Army commander speaking.
We have no reports of their movements yet.
Advance with caution.
Duce, your pigtails are in the way.
ドゥーチェ　ツインテールが邪魔です
This tank is for two. I can't see anything.
本来なら２人乗りなのに　これじゃ前見えないっすよ
Then get out, Pepperoni!
だったらペパロニ　降りろ
No way.
そりゃないっすよ
だったら耐えろ
Then deal with it.
Just take the wig off.
外せばいいじゃないっすか　そのウイッグ
It's real!
地毛だ
Really!
そうだったんっすか
痛っ
Ouch!
There they are! Found an enemy detachment.
いた
敵集団発見　ゆっくり横一列で進んできている
They're slowly advancing abreast.
了解した
Roger.
Commander, Sunflower has reached the foot of the hill.
大隊長　ひまわりは高地ふもとに達した　今　先遣隊を送っている
We've sent ahead a tank.
No enemies on the peak, I think.
頂上に敵はいないみたいだよ
We should take the hill immediately.
だったら　すぐに取るべきよ
Commander, your orders.
大隊長の判断を請う
Be very careful. It might be a trap.
罠かもしれませんから　十分に警戒してください
Spread out and advance, but be ready to retreat.
退路を確保しつつ　散開しながら前進
敵に遭遇した場合は　無理をしないようにお願いします
Don't do anything rash if you meet the enemy.
We have a powerful force here, but we must be careful not to be encircled and divided.
有利だが　包囲分断される危険性がある
We might become isolated from the other platoons.
他のチームとの連携が取れなくなるかもしれない
It's been a long time since I stood on an M26.
Ｍ26なんて登るの遅いし　ここは行くしかないわよ
We have to advance.
It's a tactically valuable position if we take it.
取れば戦術的に優位に立てますね
It is, but...
確かに優位だが　わざと山頂を空けているのかもしれない
They might be allowing us to take it on purpose.
Don't sweat it.
大丈夫よ
You don't actually trust her judgment, do you?
あなた　なんだかんだ言って　妹のこと信じてないのね
Nonna, on the other hand, has complete faith in me!
ノンナなんて　どれだけ私のこと信じてるか
If I tell her the snow is black, she will tell you it is black.
私が雪を黒いと言えば　ノンナも黒いって言うくらいよ
Right?
Yes.
はい
Belief and adoration are not the same.
信じるのと崇拝するのは違う
The longer the battle lasts,
the more their experience will count.
確かに試合が長引くと　経験の多い相手が有利だ
I want to land an early blow.
序盤で戦果を上げておきたい　行くか
Shall we go?
Yes.
はい
さあ行くわよ　203高地よ
On we go to 203 Meter Hill!
おっ　203高地ですか
203 Meter Hill!
Does Pravda know how that battle ended?
プラウダはどんな戦いか知っているのか
負ける気か
Do you want to lose?
Morning Glory, advance on Sunflower's left flank.
あさがおは　ひまわり左翼をそのまま前進してください
Okay!
ＯＫ
What shall we do?
わたくしたちは
Dandelion will advance along the foot of the hill, to Sunflower's right.
たんぽぽは　ひまわり右翼の高地脇を前進
Support them, please.
ひまわりの援護をお願いします
Lady luck favors the bold.
成功は大胆不敵の子供
We will keep nothing in reserve, then.
最初から勝負に出るのね
Hey, Nina!
ちょっとニーナ
I'm sorry!
すみませーん
Enemy detachment is advancing north towards the hill.
敵中隊　高地北上中
They will reach the top in roughly five minutes.
頂上到達まで推定５分
Shall we attack?
攻撃しますか
Let them take it.
取らせておけ
アズミ中隊　高地西の森林を全速で前進
Azumi, break through the forest west of the hill as fast as possible.
If you meet an enemy detachment,
crush them and cut off the tanks on the hill.
敵部隊と遭遇した場合は　これを突破し
中央集団後方を脅かせ
了解　中隊各車　全速前進
Roger.
All platoon tanks, full speed ahead.
Rumi, advance along the foot of
the hill until you reach the marshlands.
ルミ中隊　ふもと東方を湿原まで前進
接敵した場合は　突破せず相手をくぎづけにしろ
If you meet enemy units, pin them down.
Platoon, assume an echelon formation!
中隊　隊形を横隊から斜行陣へ
Arisa speaking.
こちらアリサ　前方に異常なし
Nothing to report ahead.
Roger.
了解
Kei to Nishi, what's your status?
ケイ車より西車へ　そっちはどう
Chihatan's detachment speaking.
こちら知波単部隊　我が部隊は順調に進撃中　右翼には敵影はなし
Our units are advancing leisurely.
No enemies visible on our right.
Fire from three o'clock!
３時方向より敵襲
CQ! CQ!
ＣＱ　ＣＱ　あさがお　敵と遭遇
Morning Glory has encountered the enemy!
Darjeeling speaking.
こちらダージリン　敵戦車発見
Enemy tanks sighted.
They're at our ten o'clock, 240 yards away.
方位10時　距離240ヤード
たんぽぽ各車　微速後退しつつ応戦
Dandelion!
Answer fire and back up.
They've come for Dandelion
and Morning Glory first!
向こうはまず　たんぽぽとあさがおを潰しに来た
11時の方向　パーシング
Pershings at eleven o'clock!
敵戦力　増大中
Enemy forces are growing!
みほさん　指示を
Miho, your orders.
Army commander to Morning Glory and Dandelion!
大隊長車より　あさがお　たんぽぽ各車へ
Don't make any maneuvers that
would give them a clear line of fire.
前後に移動を行って　相手の射線に入らないようにしてください
We will hold our positions until Sunflower reaches the peak.
高地の上に　ひまわりが到達するまで耐えましょう
Nishi! Please undertake no rash charges into the enemy.
西さん　無理な突撃は極力避けるようにお願いします
Roger.
かしこまりました
Sunflower speaking.
こちらひまわり　高地頂上に達した
We've reached the summit.
203 Meter Hill has been taken!
203　奪取よ
Miho!
みぽりん
やりましたね
They did it!
Sunflower, split into two units and support Morning Glory and Dandelion from above.
ひまわりは二手に分かれて　上からあさがおとたんぽぽの援護をお願いします
Roger.
了解　北に敵集団を確認
Enemy units to the north.
Beware of them as you support the others.
警戒しつつ支援にあたる
Open fire!
攻撃開始
Take this!
こっち来た
They're here!
一歩たりとも通すな　撃てぇ
Don't let them through!
Fire!
Arisa! Naomi! Rabbit!
アリサ　ナオミ　ラビット
Yes?
はい
They want to break
through next to the Chihatans.
チハタンズの脇から突破する気よ
Go and protect them!
前へ出て　守るわよ
Roger! I—
了解　自分が…
Taking enemy fire!
敵火力集中
進めません
We're pinned down.
Cannot support! Cannot support!
援護不能　援護不能
シット
Shit!
Bastard!
おのれぇ
Frontal assault!
突撃
負けるか
This will be the end of you!
Hey! It's too early for the attack!
コラ　突撃はまだ早い
池田車　不覚にも被弾により行動不能
Tank Ikeda. We've been taken out by enemy fire!
Tank Nagura. We were taken out gloriously!
名倉車　善戦するも撃破されました
We've lost two Chi-Has!
チハ新旧1輌ずつ撃破されました　面目次第もございません
I'm very sorry!
Morning Glory to Sunflower!
あさがおよりひまわりへ　敵に突破されたわ
The enemy has broken through our line. We're pursuing them.
現在　追撃中
Arisa, take command of the pursuit.
アリサ　追撃の指揮は頼んだわよ
Yes, Ma'am!
イェス　マムッ　動ける子はあたしについてきて
To all girls who can still move, follow—
Both tracks taken off!
左右履帯破損　砲塔故障
前に進めないよ
We can't advance!
Turret ring damaged!
Engine damaged!
We have to regroup!
態勢を立て直すわ　ハリーアップ
Hurry up!
The enemy has broken through on our left past Morning Glory and is moving into our rear!
左翼敵集団　あさがおを突破して我々の後方へ侵攻中
Support Morning Glory!
We will blow them into the ground.
あさがおを援護するわよ　蹴り落としてやる
Ready?
用意はできた
We're ready.
準備完了です
We've reached the firing point.
射点につきました
Platoon commander! Permission to fire?
中隊長　いいわね
Fire at will.
攻撃を許可する
撃てぇ
Fire!
Artillery!
だんっちゃーく
What the hell was that?!
何なのよぉ
What's happening?
どうした
こちら　ひまわり
Sunflower speaking.
Some'in' big dropped from the sky.
Maybe I'm hallucinating.
上から飛んできたっぽいぞぉー　すっごく大きいやつだと思うけど
気のせいかな
You're not!
気のせいではありません
It must be this!
きっと　これだよ　ブルムクマ
A Brummbär!
The explosion is too large.
爆発が大きすぎます
Maybe...!
もしかして　シュトゥルムティーガー
A Sturmtiger!
What is that?
何これ　弾じゃなくて人間が飛び出すの
Does it fire human beings?
380mm caliber!
380ｍｍです
Panther #1, we've been taken out!
パンターⅠ号車　撃破されました
Panther #2, we've been taken out too!
Ⅱ号車　行動不能
3発目が来る前に前進しろ
Move out before the next shell hits.
Enemy ahead is firing!
前方の敵　砲撃を開始
Retreat!
後退
もったいないけど戻るぞ
It's unfortunate, but we'll have to abandon the hill!
Not this way! Go back!
だめだ　戻れ戻れ
Huh? Are we...
あれ　これって…
We're surrounded!
包囲されてる
We're surrounded on three sides.
後方からの半包囲　上から謎の砲撃
Something strange is shelling us from
the north and their main force is ahead of us.
しかも前からは敵本隊
ここにいては全滅します
We can't stay here! We will be annihilated!
Platoon commander! Your orders! We're hit!
中隊長　どうにかしろ　やられたぁ
No you're not.
やられてないって
Descend the slope ahead.
前方斜面をこのまま下りる
Platoon, all forward! Full speed!
We will link up with Dandelion!
中隊全速前進　たんぽぽと合流するぞ
見てごらんなさい　私には当たらないわよぉ
Look at me! You cannot hit me!
パーシング接近
Pershings closing in!
何よ　狙い撃ち
Why are you all shooting at me?!
Катюша в опасности
Lady Katyusha is in danger.
Мы прорвемся, все вместе
We will break through together.
Все вместе навряд ли
We can't all make it.
мы стоим приманкой
My tank will hold them back.
Кулара, не делай глупости
Don't do something silly, Klara.
Есль ты сделаешь это, Катюша тебя разлюбит
Katyusha wouldn't want you to do that.
Есль мы прорвемся, то разлюбит это не важно
If it lets me improve our situation, I will accept that.
Hey! How many times have I told you two to speak Japanese?
あなたたち　だから日本語でしゃべりなさいって　何度言ったら分かるの
カチューシャ様　お先にどうぞ
Lady Katyusha.
Press on without me.
May you live a long life.
それでは　ごきげんよう
Whoah! You're fluent in Japanese!
何　その流暢な日本語
Klara speaks Japanese quite well.
クラーラは日本語が堪能なんです
Speak it sooner!
先に言いなさいよ
What are you doing? Klara?
何する気　クラーラ？
Klara?
クラーラ
Lady Katyusha, it has been
my honor to fight with you.
カチューシャ様　一緒に戦うことができて光栄でした
クラーラ
Klara!
За Правду!
For Pravda!
Klara!
クラーラ
They're aiming for Katyusha again...
カチューシャ様がまた狙われてら
あのちびっこ隊長には　まんずむちゃばっかさせられてきたっきゃ
They're bein' so hard
on our poor li'l commander.
We can't allow her t'be taken out 'ere.
でも　ここでやられちまっては
Ours is mighty big s'well.
なぁ　うちの車　おっきいから　盾になるんでねーか
Wanna shield her?
We gotta go.
行くべか
あぁ　行くべ　みんなもいがべ
Let's go.
Let's go together.
Yeah.
Let's go.
いぐべが
Right.
いがべしんだ
カーベーたん？
KV?
No dice.
まんだまだ
Shoot 'til the barrel runs hot!
撃てるだけ撃つべ
街道上の怪物をなめんなよ
Don't underestimate the Dreadnought!
This is bad.
まずい
Katyusha, escape.
カチューシャ　逃げてください
The commander doesn't run away!
逃げるなんて隊長じゃないわ
Please!
お願いです
来ちゃだめよ　ノンナまで失うわけにはいかないわ
Stay back!
I don't want to lose you too, Nonna!
This battle needs you.
あなたはこの試合に必要な方です
Your vision is more massive
than the Ural mountains.
あなたはウラル山脈より高い理想と　バイカル湖のように深い思慮を秘めている
The wisdom of your judgment is deeper than Lake Baikal.
Go! Retreat!
ですから　早く　撤退を
Go now!
今です
Katyusha, even without me...
カチューシャ　私がいなくとも　あなたは絶対に
you will win.
勝利します
Nonna...
ノ…ノナ
カチューシャ　何をしている
Katyusha! What are you doing?
カチューシャ様
Lady Katyusha!
Go! Go!
さっさと行けじゃ
Retreat...
撤退…
Retreat!
するわよ
Ooarai, KV-2, taken out.
大洗ＫＶ－２　行動不能
九七式中戦車1輌　同新砲塔1輌　パンター2輌
Type 97, Type 97 SHT, two Panthers,
Ooarai Prefectural Girls' Academy
University All-Stars
T-34　1輌　IS-2　1輌　KV-2　1輌　行動不能
T-34, IS-2, KV-2, taken out.
Nishi speaking.
こちら西　あさがおを突破した部隊はひまわりへの追撃を中止して
The detachment that broke through past
Morning Glory has stopped attacking Sunflower
and are linking up with the center force.
中央集団と合流中
Roger.
了解　引き続き偵察よろしく
Keep them spotted.
By the way, what were those gigantic shells?
それにしても　あの頭上からの砲撃は…
I think I know what it was.
おそらく　あれです
What do you mean...? No!
あれ？　まさか
How do you know?
何で分かるの
Did you break their code as well?
また盗聴
You seem like the type to spy on your boyfriend.
アリサさんって彼氏のことも盗聴しそうだよね
The clingy type, huh?
束縛しすぎ？
Takashi dumped her.
それでタカシに振られたんだ
I didn't even ask him out!
He couldn't dump me!
告白もしてないのに　振られるわけないじゃない
How do you even know all that?
っていうか　何で知ってるのよ
Cheer up, Arisa.
アリサさん　元気出してくださいね　一人も楽しいですよ
Being alone can be fun too.
You can do it!
ファイト
It's no big deal!
ドンマイ
戦車が恋人でいいじゃないですか
Just think of the tank as your boyfriend!
うるさいわね　あなたたちに慰められたくないわ
Shuddup! I don't want you to console me!
それより
Stop it.
Did they really have that tank approved?
あの車輌は認可されたの
They were debating it when we talked to them.
うちが導入しようとして問い合わせた時は協議中だったんですが
Sunflower has escaped,
but only has five tanks left.
ひまわり　脱出したけど　あと5輌だって
戦闘を中止して　ひまわりと合流しますか
Do you want to pull back and link up?
でも　先に頭上からの砲撃をなんとかしないと
We need to do something about these shells from above first.
Going by the travel time and the explosion,
発射の時と着弾の音から推察すると　砲弾はおそらく1トン以上の艦砲クラス
I would say it's a naval gun with shells heavier than one metric ton.
We didn't hear the shriek of a rocket motor,
でもロケット推進音はなかったから　シュトゥルムティーガーじゃない　とすると…
so it isn't a Sturmtiger.
That means...!
Prez, Isobe, Anchovy, Mika.
会長　磯辺さん　アンチョビさん　ミカさん　お願いしたいことがあります
I have something to ask of you.
Team Acorn!
どんぐり小隊　全速前進
Drive as fast as you can!
All right, Antchovy!
お待たせ　チョビー
Don't call me that!
チョビって呼ぶな
Four of their tanks are advancing.
4輌　前進してきます
They are probably trying to
take out the commander's tank.
おそらく隊長車狙いかと
I believe they want to disrupt our chain of command.
こちらの指揮系統を混乱させるつもりか　破れかぶれなのか
Looks like a Hail Mary to me.
All tanks, fire. Don't let them close to the commander.
各車発砲　隊長に近寄らすな
Where are they?
消えた？
It's a feint.
陽動だ　させておけ
Ignore them.
What is that?!
何だ　あれは
カールっすよ
It's a Karl!
Karl Wolff?
カールヴォルフ
Not him.
違います
じゃあ　カールって何だ
Then what Karl?
The Karl-Gerät!
カール自走臼砲っす　あれは600ｍｍ砲っすよ
It's a 600mm self-propelled mortar!
6-0-0?!
ろっぴゃくう？
The Carro Veloce has an 8mm machine gun, so it's...
カルロベローチェが８ｍｍ機銃だから　えーと　何倍だ？
how many times bigger?
割り算もできないんすか　7.5倍っす
Can't you divide that?
It's 7.5 times!
It's 75 times.
75倍です
Did you force us to approve it at
the last minute specifically for this battle?
これを直前になって認可させたのは　この試合のためだったんですな
Pure coincidence. Please stop with the accusations.
言いがかりはよしていただきたい
しかしオープントップなのに　戦車と認めていいんですか
But it's open-top. Is it even a tank?
It depends on how you look at it.
考え方次第ですよ
Three Pershings are guarding the Karl!
パーシングが3輌　カールを守ってるよ
Prez! We need to pull back!
会長　撤退しましょう
We could break through with four tanks.
4輌で突っ込むか
No way!
無理です
Nobody would ever eat pasta raw!
それはパスタをなまで食べるくらいむちゃだ
We have to retreat!
撤退しかありません
Wait!
待ってください　いい考えがあります
I have a plan!
Don't tell me we have to ride another tank again!
まさかまた戦車の上に乗るのか
Sounds good.
いいね
違います
No.
There's no way to get up
high enough for the Karl.
カールに上がれる方法ないですから
Our idea was...
私たちが考えたのは
Operation Murder Receive!
殺人レシーブ作戦です　作戦内容は…
This is how it goes...
Bastards!
おのれぇ
Rosehip...
ローズヒップ　戻りなさい
Come back.
That sounds good.
それ　いいね
Really?
そうですかぁ
Did you hear that, Continuation?
継続ちゃーん　聞いてた　ちょっと手伝ってほしいんだけど
We want you to help us.
It seems like such a pointless plan.
この作戦に意味があるとは思えない
じゃあ　従わないの
Do you want to disobey them?
But let us believe in their judgment.
しかし彼女たちの判断を信じよう
Let's go.
いくぞ
Platoon, chase them!
小隊　追うぞ
Is this battle an important part of our lives?
これは人生にとって必要な戦いなの
おそらくね
Most likely.
今だ
Now!
しまったぁ
Oh no!
Don't worry. We will blow
them into tiny fragments!
大丈夫　木っ端微塵にしてやるわ
It's looking at us!
こっち見てるぞ
残り1輌
Only one of them is left!
Mikko, left.
ミッコ　左
What?! Without tracks?!
何　履帯なしなのに
Bow down before the Christie suspension!
天下のクリスティ式　なめんなよ
Go!
いっけー
Special move!
必殺　殺人レシーブ
Murder Receive!
We did it!
やった
We're so smart!
かしこいね　私たち
今だ　マズルを狙え
Fire!
Aim for the muzzle!
あれ
Huh?
Ready!
よーい
And we threw them so well...
せっかく踏み台になったのに
The plan has failed! Retreat!
作戦失敗だ　撤退しろ
Shit.
くっそ
Antchovy! Get your tracks going!
チョビ子　履帯を回転させろ
Don't order me!
命令するな　私を誰だと思って
Who do you think I am?
干し芋パスタを作ってやるからさ
I'll make you pasta with dried potatoes.
Pasta!
パスタ
Really?
マジっすか
よし
Okay!
飛べぇ
Fly!
Prez! It's all on you!
会長　お願いします
All right!
やった
Tulta!
トゥルタ
I wish you good fortune
in the rest of the battle.
皆さんの健闘を祈ります
BT-42, 2 Panthers, T-34, IS-2, KV-2, Chi-Ha SHT, Chi-Ha.
BT-42　パンター2輌　T-34　IS-2　KV-2　チハ新旧1輌ずつ
We've lost eight tanks.
合計8輌が撃破されました
But we've taken out
the Karl and five Pershings.
でもでも　こっちはカールとパーシング5輌を撃破したよ
So it's 22 against 24 now.
これで22対24ですね
There's fewer and fewer of us.
ずいぶん減ったね
I'm actually impressed
how well we held out.
いや　よく持ちこたえたほうだ
Continuation did a lot for us.
継続さんが頑張ってくれましたよね
We did too!
うちもな
Of course!
もちろんです
The volleyball club and the Prez made it possible.
バレー部さんと会長さんたちのおかげです
Nishizumi, I'm truly sorry that two
of our tanks abandoned the line of battle.
西住さん　我が校は2輌も戦列を離れてしまい　誠に申し訳ございません
It's okay...
I've lost them all...
うちはカチューシャだけになっちゃった
Don't worry.
大丈夫
You're still here, Katyusha.
まだ　あなたが残ってるわ　カチューシャ
I know that!
分かってるわよ
This was my fault.
すみません　私の責任です　互角に持ち込めると思ったんですけど
I thought we were evenly matched.
You were too predictable.
定石どおり　やりすぎたな　らしくもない
You can do better.
Choose the tactic you think is best.
みほの戦いをすればいいんだ
What's the plan now, Army Commander?
ここからの作戦は　大隊長
We'll draw them to the buildings, then use our commanders' strengths to take them out together.
局地戦に持ち込んで　個々の特長を生かして　チームワークで戦いましょう
Teamwork with such a ragtag group?
急造チームでチームワーク
Ragtag or not, we're still a team.
急造でもチームはチームだ　互いに足りないところを補い合って　戦うしかない
We'll compensate for each others' weaknesses. It's all we can do.
We will regroup and head over there.
チームを再編成して　あそこを目指します
OK.
ＯＫ
It will be easier to ambush them there.
あの中だと　遭遇戦がやりやすくなります
That's true.
確かにそうね
That'll make it our last stand.
でも背水の陣になるわ
We're good at that kind of thing.
そういう戦い得意だよ　うちは
Anzio too!
アンツィオも得意だ
We are?
そっすか
All right.
では　パンツァーフォー
Panzer vor!
Why must we retreat to such a remote place?
こんな辺鄙な所まで撤退するとは
We're not retreating, Tamada.
It's a front adjustment.
違う　玉田　これは転進だ
I see! A front adjustment!
なるほど　転進ですか
I believe this will be a rather amusing battle.
面白い戦いになりそうね
Excuse me, but the statistics predict a harsh engagement.
お言葉ですが　データの上では厳しい戦いになりそうです
We knew what we were getting into.
覚悟の上じゃないですか
Fortune is a fickle ally.
運命は浮気者　不利なほうが負けるとは限らないわ
It's not always the stronger one who wins.
Right, Commander?
ね　隊長
Exactly.
はい　私たちは　私たちにできる戦いをしましょう
Let's do what we do best.
私たちにできる戦い
What we do best...
And what is that?
何だろう
A frontal attack?
突撃　いや違う
No...
全軍　遊園地跡に移動
Their forces have all entered
the abandoned theme park.
We've taken up positions at the main gate to the south.
南正門入り口　配置完了
We're at the back gate in the west. All ready.
西裏門　こちらも配置済みであります
東通用門　こちらも固めたわ
We're at the side gate in the east.
We will defend it.
We need another three minutes to
set up positions in the central plaza.
中央広場　あと3分で整備終わるよ
Duce, are you serious?
ドゥーチェ　マジっすか
I'm serious.
マジだ
Won't they see us?
敵に見つかりませんか
The tankette is small.
We will be hard to spot.
タンケッテは小さいから　見つかりにくい
And if they spot us, we can't run away.
見つかったら　逃げ場ありませんけどね
The enemy is approaching
the southern gate in a large group.
敵は南正門にまとまって進撃中
It looks like they'll try
a deep battle breakthrough.
縦深突破ですかね
Platoon one, move to the southern gate.
第一陣は南正門に移動してください
北裏門　東通用門の皆さんも　警戒を怠らないようにしてください
If you're protecting the back or
side gates, don't let your guard down.
Saunders will remain on standby.
サンダースの皆さんは待機
They'll be here in another three minutes or so.
あと３分くらいかな
They're throwing up a lot of dust there.
にしても　あいつら　ずいぶんかっ飛ばしてますね
I think they're trying to intimidate us
by producing that huge cloud.
あえて大げさに土煙を立てるように走って　威圧感を出そうとしてるのかもしれないな
It's a kind of bluff, huh?
はったりかましてるんすね　うちのマカロニ作戦みたいなもんだ
Like Operation Macaroni.
It's pretty different.
違うと思います
Prepare for battle.
戦闘準備
They're coming.
来るよ　みんな落ち着いてね
Calm down, everyone.
撃て
Fire!
Shit.
くそ　全然見えないぞ
I can't see anything.
Oh, man. I wanna be down there and shoot stuff.
いいな　うちらもどハデに戦いたいな
This is a little strange, though. It just rained and they're still kicking up a lot of dust.
でも変ですね　雨が上がってまもないのに　あんなに土煙
That's not dust.
これは土煙じゃないぞ
Shit! They're tricking us!
くそっ　だまされた
Commander! This is a feint! That's a smoke screen!
隊長　陽動作戦だ　あの煙は煙幕だ
Stratagem Number Six, "Make a sound in the east, then strike in the west".
兵法第６計「声東撃西」ですね
Stradajem?
へーほー？
西裏門の西さん　敵が回り込もうとしています
West gate, the enemy is trying to move around.
Saunders will reinforce you.
サンダースの皆さんが応援に向かいますので　戦闘準備　お願いします
Prepare for battle.
Roger.
かしこまりました
Rush them when they show up!
よーし　敵が見えたら　全力で突っ込んでやる
It's time to clear our name!
先ほどの面目を果たす時が来た
知波単名物　総突撃
The time for our famous tactic has come! Frontal assault!
恐れながら申し上げます
Pray excuse me!
I believe that launching a doomed frontal assault would only add to Chihatan's shame.
いたずらに突撃して全滅しては　それこそ知波単の面目に関わるかと
What?!
何だと
Fukuda, are you insulting our traditions?!
福田　伝統をないがしろにする気か
I'm very sorry!
申し訳ございません
Calm down.
まあ　待て
Fukuda. Do you have an idea?
福田　何か策があるんだな
Time to fight their Chaffee fair and square!
チャーフィー　いざ尋常に勝負
Come back, Rosehip!
戻りなさい　ローズヒップ
Goodness gracious!
何てこった　Ｔ28重戦車がいるぞ
It's a T-28 heavy tank.
T-28? Which one?!
Ｔ28って　どれ
This one?
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
これかな
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
It's a heavy tank... So this one?
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
重戦車だから　こちらでは
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Medium
Tank
3 Turrets
1   76mm
4 Machine Guns
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
Super Heavy Tank
Ways to tell apart
* Long main gun
H
* Low and flat
* No turret
R
* Sluggish
like a turtle
S
R
Two tracks per side
500 PS gasoline engine
Powerful 105mm main gun!!
We should have brought a Tortoise.
わたくしたちもトータスを持ってくればよかったわ
持ってませんけど
But we didn't.
Duce speaking!
こちらドゥーチェ　こりゃあ間違いなくこっちが主力だぞ
I'm sure this part is their main force.
Saunders, please go to the eastern side gate.
サンダースの皆さん　東通用門に向かってください
Already on the way!
もう向かってるよ
Ooarai will reinforce you.
大洗のチームも増援へ
うちもＴ28改造キット欲しいなぁ
I want a T-28 conversion kit.
There aren't any!
売ってません
It's like Jabberwocky.
まるでジャバウォッキーです
More like the Bandersnatch.
というよりもバンダースナッチね
Here we are.
お待たせ
うわ　でかい
It's huge!
Second block, fall back.
２ブロック後退
Megumi speaking. We've broken through the eastern side gate.
こちらメグミ中隊　東通用門突破　予定通りＺ地点に向かいます
We will advance on point Z as planned.
了解
Roger.
Nishi! Our friends are in danger!
西隊長　味方の危機ですよ　直ちに総攻撃に向かうべきでは
We need to mount a frontal assault at once!
そう言うな　玉田　これも作戦だ
No, Tamada.
This is also part of the plan.
They only have four tanks.
4輌しかいないわね　私たちを引き付けておくだけみたいだけど
I think they're only trying to pin us down.
What shall we do?
どうする
Okay. Let's go.
分かった　行こう
Take point, Erika.
エリカ　頼む
Roger!
はい
敵影なし
No enemies in sight.
No enemies on the other shore.
対岸にも敵影なし
Enemy sighted!
敵発見
Go! Now!
よし　今だ
Well done, Tamada!
玉田　よくやった
All right! Attack!
よし　もういっちょ
それくらいにしておけ
That's enough!
って　あれ
Huh?
Pull back!
戻れ
おのれ
You bastard!
Retrograde advance!
後退的前進
Their goal is to disrupt our formation with
superior firepower and destroy the individual units.
相手の狙いは　火力で私たちをかく乱して　各個撃破することです
We won't let them divide us!
ばらばらになんかさせないわよ
We've abandoned the southern
main gate and are fleeing north.
こちら南正門軍　北へ敗走中
Western back gate, we've repaired our tracks.
西裏門軍　履帯修復完了
The enemy is unexpectedly using defense in depth and guerrilla warfare.
敵は予想外にも縦深防御によって　遊撃戦を仕掛けています
Change of plans.
作戦を変更する
If they don't want to be divided up,
let them fight together.
分散がいやなら　望みどおりにしてやろう
Roger.
了解
How much longer, Commander Nishi?
西隊長　まだでありますか
Just wait.
そろそろ頃合いかと
We should attack.
Wait!
I'm reaching the limit of my patience!
もはや我慢の限界であります
Stop struggling! The balloons are fragile!
コラ　むやみに動くんじゃない　風船はデリケートなんだぞ
しまった　撤退的前進
Oh, crap!
Retrograde advance!
There it is!
出た
Run!
逃げろ
Hey, not there!
ちょっと　そっちじゃない
気をつけて　挟まれるわよ
Be careful. They want to surround us.
Escape into the western alley!
西の路地に逃げ込んで　正面ドームを逆時計回りに
Go counterclockwise around the dome!
Roger!
Okay!
はい
Where's west?
西ってどっち
I don't know!
分かんない
Main Gate platoon!
こちら正門チーム　チャーフィーの動きに仕組まれた何かを感じる
I think the Chaffee we are chasing is plotting something. The Side Gate platoon should beware.
通用門組は注意せよ
うーん　気づいてるのに　無視されている気がしないでもないのだが　気のせいかな
I have the vague but inescapable
feeling that we are being ignored.
Rear guard speaking.
Gunfire behind us is quite sporadic.
こちら最後尾　追尾攻撃は散発的　妙ね
It's quite strange.
Wow!
すごーい　パーシングを立て続けに撃破したよ　みんな頑張ってるね
They took out two Pershings!
They're doing their best.
Sometimes that is not enough.
頑張ればいいってもんじゃない
Why do you always have to be so contrary?
何でそんなにひねくれたことばっかり言うのよ
Look.
よーく見てごらん
Isn't this bad?
これ　まずくないですか
Miho!
みぽりん
Oh, no!
やっべー
No! Don't go there!
だめだだめだ　そっちはだめだぞ
Miho! The Side Gate platoon
is being surrounded at point YO.
西住さん　通用門組がＹＯ地点にて包囲されようとしています
分かりました　すぐに向かいます
Roger. We will go there now.
Southern Main Gate and Western Back Gate platoons, go to point YO.
南正門組　西裏門組　ＹＯ地点に向かってください
We will be there too.
こちらも駆けつけます　包囲網の完成を阻止してください
Make sure they aren't completely encircled.
Roger.
分かった
We've been had!
謀られた　やつらも合流する気だな　道理でいつまで待っても来ないわけだ
They want to link up too!
No wonder they're not showing up!
We got lost...
迷っちゃった
行け　楔を打ち込め
Go! Drive a wedge into them!
包囲完了
We have them encircled.
一方的すぎて心苦しいわ
It was so one-sided, I almost felt bad.
We will end this for you.
あとは私たちに任せてください
I'm not sure what's going on, but aren't they surrounded?
なんか知らないけど　先輩たち　囲まれてない
Oh, no!
やばーい
Let's attack and take them all out!
突撃して敵をやっつけよう
We'll never manage that.
1輌だけじゃ無理
But we have to do something.
でも　助けないと
Saki, tell us about the butterfly later.
さき　ちょうちょはあとにして　今は試合中だからね
We're in battle.
The Ferris wheel.
観覧車
Yes! The Ferris wheel!
そうか　観覧車といえば
Right!
そっか
All right...
よーし
Execute Operation Mifune!
ミフネ作戦　行きます
Fire!
撃て
We did it!
やった
Saki, you're a genius!
さきちゃん　天才
Huh?
あれ
退却
Run!
Hey!
ちょっと　同じ方向に逃げてどうすんの
You have to get out of the way!
そっか
Right!
What's that sound?
何だ？
Evasive maneuvers!
退避行動
A tsar tank!
ツァーリタンクか
A Panjandrum!
パンジャンドラム
Wow!
こっち来るぞ
Run!
逃げろ
Get away!
Hm, that's so weird!
あら　変ですわ
「変ですわ」じゃない
It's not!
余計なことすんな
Don't mess with it!
Run!
逃げろ
Fire!
Now!
今だ　あとに続け
Follow me!
What shall we do, Commander?
このあとどうします　隊長
They're almost at the amusement areas,
so let's go with plan F.
相手がほぼ園内に侵入したので　プランＦで戦います
Leave the GPS guidance to me!
GPS役なら任せとけ
We will divide our forces even more than
they do, so be mindful of where your allies are.
相手以上に　こちらが分散するので　見えない仲間の把握に心がけてください
はい
Roger!
観覧車さん　力尽きそうね
Our friend the Ferris wheel
is running out of steam.
Thank you, Ferris wheel!
観覧車先輩　お疲れ様でした
Bye, Ferry.
バイバイ　かんちゃん
Be well.
達者でな
See you!
シーユー
So, what is it we can do here?
結局さあ　私たちにできることって何だろう
We're the heavy tank killer!
重戦車キラー
No...
違うと思う
Let's fight in a way cut out for us.
もっと身の丈にあった戦い方をしようよ
Such as?
たとえば？
You're close to a good spot.
おあつらえの場所が近いぞ
Do what we talked about!
例のやつ　発動だ
We're going in first.
先に行くぜよ
Time to change clothes.
お色直しでござる
This looks good.
これか
おーい　今は逃げる時だよ　カチューシャ
Hey, we're running away right now, Katyusha.
Address me properly!
呼び捨てにしないでよ
Okay, Katy.
じゃあ　カッちゃん
Don't shorten it!
何　略してんの
We need to hurry, Katy.
いいからカっちゃん　急ぐぞよ
You guys can run away!
逃げるんなら　あんたたちだけ逃げなさい　私はここで戦う
I'll fight here!
Don't act strong, Katy.
力むなよ　カッちゃん
We're fighting together.
戦うのはみんなで　だよ
Nonna and the others are gone!
ノンナさんたちはいなくなったもも
We're here for you now.
私たちがいるぴよ
今は同じチームだにゃー
We're a team now.
Yeah.
そーそー　大洗の興廃　この一戦にあり　各員一層奮励努力せよ
The fate of the motherschool
rests on our shoulders!
I expect that every girl will do her duty!
Tamada speaking.
I can't breathe! I won't last long...
玉田　息が詰まって　体がもたないであります
Rest easy. We've called
for the best backup possible.
ご安心ください　最強の助っ人をお呼びしました
My family!
本家参上
They're here!
来ましたでございますのよ
All correct!
オールコレクト　マスターアームオン
Master arm, on!
Fire!
ファイヤー
Passed down directly from Anzio!
Operation Macaroni Zwei! Success!
アンツィオ直伝　マカロニ作戦ツヴァイ　大成功
All right! To the next point!
よーし　次　行ってみよう
The cavalry is attacking!
騎兵隊が襲ってくるにょ
Wolololololo...
I'll get you!
やったわね
今はチームプレイだよ　そど子
We have to play as a team now, Sodoko!
Master arm, on!
マスターアームオン
Fire!
ファイヤー
To the next point!
次　行ってみよ
They're all around us, Geronimo!
囲まれますぜ　ジェロニモ
What will we do, Geronimo!
どうします　ジェロニモ
Who's Geronimo here?!
誰がジェロニモよ
Go through the buildings!
建物の中　突っ切っちゃって
セットみたいなものだから　大丈夫
It's like a movie set! Don't worry!
ハウ　了解　ジェロニモ
How! Roger, Geronimo!
Nekonya!
ねこっ　にゃっ
Piyotan!
ぴよ　たん
Momoga!
Ｆクイック　いくよ
Let's do a quick F!
Agility Plan Number Six, right?
敏捷作戦第6号ですね　準備完了であります
We're ready!
しまった
Oh, no!
Get away!
この
Ignore them! Aim for the other!
構うな　前を狙え
Oh, no!
しまった
Well done, Tamada!
玉田　お見事
アヒル殿　次はどうしたら
What now, Duck?
A knuckle serve from above,
then a double block and a spike!
天井からのナックルサーブで
ダブルブロックからの近距離スパイク
Roger!
かしこまりました
The barrel will touch the ground!
砲身が刺さるぞ
Turn the turret to avoid damage!
旋回してダメージ回避
Okay!
はい
Attack them, Fuku!
アタック　福ちゃん
了解であります
Roger!
Double block!
ダブルブロック
Push with all you've got!
根性で押せ
Okay!
はい
How's that?!
どうだ
I don't think that does any good.
やっぱり意味ないと思いますよ
I, Hosomi, will take them out!
不肖細見　参ります
Nice move!
ナイスファイトー
They can't turn their turret in these narrow lanes.
この道幅なら　砲塔の旋回はできない
Just stick to them and don't let them get away.
あとにぴったりついたら　絶対に離れるな
Roger.
分かりました
I'm sorry, Rumi!
すみません　ルミ隊長　撃破されました
They took us out!
I request backup of one Pershing and one Chaffee.
パーシング　チャーフィー　各1輌　増援を要請する
Surround them with numbers.
数の利を生かして囲い込め
The Hetzer has a very low profile. Be careful of ambushes.
車高の低いヘッツァーの待ち伏せに注意しつつ
The Pz. IV is the main target!
まずはⅣ号だ
Hey! Be careful!
コラ　気をつけろ
Sorry!
あー　すいません
I think they know our movements...
こちらを見通しているかのような動きだ　天性の勘なのか
Does she just have godly intuition?
Then let's herd them into a dead end.
ならば袋小路に追い詰めるか
All right! They're cornered!
よし　追い詰めた
なぜだ　勘がいいってレベルじゃないぞ　これは
But how? That's not a matter of intuition anymore.
They're spotting!
あいつらが
The other team is like you.
あっちのチームはあんたね　どれだけボコボコになっても立ち向かってくる
I can mess them up as much as I want, but they'll still stand up again.
They're not strong at all, but they never give up.
決して強くはないのに諦めない
We've taken a lot of losses against these high schoolers.
まさか　ここまで高校生がやるとは
They're so shrewd!
こざかしいったら　ありゃしない
What should we do now?
どうする
I don't want to run crying to our commander.
ここで隊長に泣きつくなんて
But if we don't admit we're outmatched, then...
でも自分たちのメンツばかり言ってたら
I'll do it, I swear I will
やってやる　やってやる　やってやるぜ
I tear those jerks up good
イヤなあいつをボコボコに
Fights are meant to be picked
ケンカは売るもの　堂々と
I'll turn 'round and dress 'em down
肩で風きり　啖呵きる
The commander is singing!
隊長が歌い出した
That means...
ということは
It's not a problem...
Platoon forward!
中隊前進
The T-28 is advancing!
Ｔ28がやってきます
The gate is too narrow.
この門はあの車体には狭すぎるでしょう
It stripped down?!
脱いだ
Master arm, on!
マスターアームオン
Fool me twice.
それはない
Feuer!
ファイヤ
Why?!
なぜだ
完璧だったのに
It was perfect!
The Centurion is advancing through the Western back gate. Be careful!
西裏門より　センチュリオン侵入
注意しろ
了解しました
Roger.
They've found us.
しまった　バレたぞ
That takes guts.
気合　入ってんな
Stay calm. The rails narrow here, so they won't be able to follow us.
落ち着いて行け　この先は細いから　ついてこれない
I have no idea what's going
on anymore! Run at full speed!
なんか知らんけど　全開で逃げろ
They're showing really serious guts.
超気合　入ってますね
それから　向き変えて応戦
We should turn around and fire back!
We can't!
無理です
There they are! All tanks forward!
来たぞ　戦車前進
This is like the attack at Hiyodorigoe!
鵯越ですな
Fire!
撃て
あ　いた
Oh, no!
今だ
Now!
Okay!
はい
I'm sorry!
申し訳ありません
It's okay!
ドンマイ
To battle, my sisters!
超根性
This is how we always lose.
この負けっぷり　いつもの我々ですな
And to a worthy foe!
敵ながら　あっぱれ
Take it more seriously!
のんきに言わないでください
I'm looking at the data right now. The weak point is here.
データによりますと　ウイークポイントはここです
That's a little hard to reach elegantly.
優雅な勝ち方にはほど遠いですね
We've come here to help Miho.
今回はみほさんを助けに来たのよ　私たちの勝利じゃない
Sacrifices must be made at times.
17-pounder, are you ready?
17ポンド砲さん　準備はどう
とっくにできてる
Have been for a long time.
いくぞ
I'll fire.
どうぞ
Please do.
成功ね　アッサムのデータ主義もたまにはいいものね
Success.
Your insistence on data
has paid off for once, Assam.
Sadly, the data indicates a rather low probability for survival now.
ですがデータによりますと　このあとの生還率が
You can do it, Miho.
みほさん頑張って　戦いは最後の5分間にあるのよ
The battle is decided in the last five minutes.
We should be pressuring them
much more. Shall we assemble?
チマチマしているのは性に合わないわ　集まりましょうか
Let them feel...
いつもどおりの
our Bermuda attack!
バミューダアタック
They're a persistent bunch.
しつこいな
無限ループですね
These rails are a circle, I think.
ドゥーチェ　前
Duce, ahead!
They have us!
挟まれたっす
どうする　どうするっていうか撃て
What now? Just shoot I guess!
Okay!
はい
All right!
よっしゃ
次いくよ　次
Now for the next one...
Fire!
撃て
We're the light tank killer!
さすが軽戦車キラー
Hey! What happened?
What just happened?
え　なになに　何があったの
分かんなーい
I don't know!
Did we hit a landmine?
地雷？
No, the enemy took us out.
違う　敵にやられたの
The Centurion is coming for you!
センチュリオンが向かっています
Let's blow them away
and meet with the commander!
一気に蹴散らして　隊長と合流するわよ
Stop there!
ストップ
Fire!
ファイヤー
おーのれ
You bastards!
Whoops.
ウップス
They got us!
やられた
Momoga!
ももがっ
しまったもも
Oh, no!
リミっター　外しちゃいますわよ
I'll turn off the limiter!
Head for the central plaza.
目標　中央広場
Roger.
はい
Let's go together, sis.
お姉ちゃん　こっちもコンビネーションでいこう
分かった
Roger.
ヘイ　タクシー
Hey, taxi!
Get on!
はいはーい
体当たりでもいいから　センチュリオンとの合流を阻止するわよ
Ram them if you must! Make sure
they don't link up with the Centurion!
Shit!
くそ
Found a stray Pershing!
野原パーシング発見
Are they hunting down stragglers?
残党狩り係でしょうか
How dare they?!
こしゃくな　挟み撃ちするぞ
Let's surround them and take them out.
了解
Roger!
Should we really be doing this?
勝手なことしちゃっていいの　これじゃ規則違反してるみたい
I think it's against the rules.
規則は破るためにあるのよ
Rules are meant to be broken!
We won't be able to catch up.
I'll overload the engine!
このままじゃ追いつけないから　パワー出すよ
Slip through behind us.
スリップでついてきてね　よろしく
Okay.
Slip through how?
スリップするのか
In the slipstream, right?
スリップストリームね
Hey!
このぉ　あれ
Huh?
Hah! You don't have the gun depression!
俯角　取れないでやんの
豆戦車を踏み潰せ
Crush their skulls under our iron tracks!
All right! Operation T Ruler!
よーし　Ｔ型定規作戦だ
It's never worked!
一回も成功したことないっすよ
停止
Stop!
Don't worry. It's really shallow.
安心して　浅瀬だから
We did it! It worked!
やった　成功だ　タンケッテ最強
Tankettes are awesome!
Ah, you will never catch up to me, simpletons.
そんなんじゃ　いつまでたっても追いつけないよ　ノロマさんたち
The rules limit the engines' output, but not the traction motors'!
エンジン規定はあるけど　モーターはないもんね
超频
隐形
垂直起降
Go, Speed Racer!
行け　超音速の貴公子
あれ
IV号H
Tiger I
A41百夫长
M26潘兴
Ooarai Prefectural Girls' Academy
University All-Stars
Okay.
はい
分かりました
Understood.
Will we be okay?
大丈夫
Mako, we can do it.
麻子さんも　よろしく
All right.
おうよ
Forward!
前進
A blank?!
空砲
Centurion, Pz. IV, immobilized.
センチュリオン　Ⅳ号　走行不能
Counting remaining tanks.
残存車輌確認中
Visual confirmation.
目視確認　終了
University All-Stars, no remaining tanks.
大学選抜　残存車輌なし
Ooarai Girls' Academy, one remaining tank.
大洗女子学園　残存戦車１
Ooarai Girls' Academy has won!
大洗女子学園の勝利
よっしゃ　お嬢
All right!
What? We won?
えっ　何　勝ったの
Harasho! Pirozhki!
Хорошо! Пирожки!!
Banzai!
バンザーイ
Yay!
イエーイ
Победа!
Victory!
Молодцы!
We did it!
これで廃校はなくなった
We've avoided being shut down!
西住ちゃーん
Nishizumi!
Thank you!
ありがとう
We won! Goddamn, we won!
勝った　勝ったぞ
隊長　お疲れ様でした
Well done, Commander.
Thanks.
Congratulations, Miho.
みほさん　おめでとう
Congratulations!
おめでとう
Congratulations.
ま　おめでとう
That was a good battle.
いい試合だった
皆さん　本当にありがとうございました
Thank you so much, everyone.
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました
I would like to thank you as well!
こちらこそ　お礼を言わせていただきたいです
This is my medal for you.
私からの勲章よ
Thank you.
ありがとう　大切にするね
I'll treasure it forever.
I would like them to battle without deeper meaning next time.
次からは　わだかまりのない試合をさせていただきたいですね
Aye.
まったく
Panzerfahren really features every important part of life.
戦車道には本当に人生の大切なことが詰まってるね
It does, doesn't it?
だろう
瞳閉じて　耳を澄ませば聞こえる
When I close my eyes and listen,
I can hear a voice still young
Together we talked about silly things and laughed
他愛もないおしゃべりで何時間でも
for hours on end
笑っていられたね
The sunlight-flooded corridor,
光差す渡り廊下も　チャイムの音色も
the sound of the school bell...
It's all a part of what connected
曖昧で確かな日々を繋ぐ　大切なピース
those fuzzy days
Back then, we had no map
あの頃のぼくらはまだ　明日の地図さえ持たずに
for what tomorrow would hold,
but we wanted to do something new
新しい何かを探してたんだね
We had blurry visions for our future
描いてた淡い夢も　不意に触れた優しさも
and learned what it meant to be there for another
All those things
その一つ一つが　ほら　ぼくらの「今」を作ってる
now make us who we are
One day, after so many seasons had passed,
何度目かの季節が巡ったある日
I stopped in my tracks and realized
ふと立ち止まって気付く
that we were all walking down different roads,
目の前には　それぞれ違う色した
each with its own set of colors
道があったんだね
After school, when we met,
読みかけの本のしおりも　中庭の花も
the wind blew the bookmark I used into the sky
風に煽られてふわりと舞う　いつもの放課後
together with the flowers around me,
where they twirled and danced
Back then, we...
あの頃のぼくらは…
Back then, we had no map,
あの頃のぼくらはまだ　明日の地図さえ持たずに
for what tomorrow would hold,
but we wanted to look for something new
新しい何かを探してたんだね
Our friendship will not fade
変わらない友情も　果たせなかった約束も
We couldn't keep a lot of promises,
その一つ一つが　ほら　ぼくらの「未来」作ってく
but all those things
Donated by
Alice Shimada
now make up our future